<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Books - Tough Guy Book Club</title>
    <description/>
    <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/books</link>
    <item>
      <title>World War Z - Max Brooks (2006)</title>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;This holiday break we are reading World War Z by Max Brooks.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Grab a copy and get reading.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;See you in Feb.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="noopener" href="https://booktopia.kh4ffx.net/21LYXa" target="_blank"&gt;Buy It Here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img style="width: 30%; float: right; margin-left: 20px;" src="https://assets.nationbuilder.com/tgbc/pages/321/attachments/original/1702510384/wwz.jpg?1702510384" alt="" width="100%" height="auto" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 19:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <author>Peter Machell</author>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/world_war_z</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At the Mountains of Madness - H. P. Lovecraft (1931)</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This month we are reading At The Mountains of Madness by H P Lovecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://booktopia.kh4ffx.net/m5JoR1"&gt;Buy from Booktopia.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img style="width: 30%; float: right; margin-left: 20px;" src="https://assets.nationbuilder.com/tgbc/pages/312/attachments/original/1700736587/65436549442cb130888054.jpg?1700736587" alt="" width="100%" height="auto" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <author>Peter Machell</author>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/at_the_mountains_of_madness</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Water - Caleb Azumah Nelson (2021)</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;img style="width: 30%; float: right; margin-left: 20px;" src="https://assets.nationbuilder.com/tgbc/pages/311/attachments/original/1700802737/open_water.jpg?1700802737" alt="" width="100%" height="auto" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open Water is an ambitious and at times confronting novel that contrasts a modern story of young love against a broader social commentary on racial prejudice and masculinity. The book is deeply lyrical, with poetic passages and refrains that echo the book's soundtrack of hip hop references that are littered throughout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://booktopia.kh4ffx.net/MmvRno"&gt;Buy a copy at Booktopia.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story follows two young people who are falling in love in London in 2017. After meeting in a pub in South East London, they circle around each other, initially unsure of what their feelings mean or where they are going. Both are Black British, and have experienced alienation after winning scholarships to prestigious, predominantly white private schools. Now, as artists, they are struggling to make sense of a society which is at once their home and a place that, at times, violently rejects them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the most obvious element of the novel, when you first read it, is that it's written in the second person. The strong 'you' of the narrator is a little unsettling at first, but it works to put your right in the shoes of the protagonist. As the novel goes on, I think that Azumah Nelson's narrator is really speaking to himself, and finding a language to work through what he has experienced. The protagonist frequently remarks that words are insufficient, and his journey reflects the author's attempt to describe the struggle to express the experience of trauma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I read the book, I was drawn into the love story but found the elements of trauma and racial discrimination quite confronting and jarring. On reflection, I think Azumah Nelson is doing something important in exploring how this kind of trauma can come to insidiously infect every aspect of a person's life. This book is particularly poignant in our current climate, following the Black Lives Matter movement and, more recently in Australia, the Voice Referendum, as Open Water deals explicitly not just with race but with the broader experience of people being and feeling unseen and unheard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book's interrogation of masculinity is also central, as the protagonist struggles, and almost refuses, to open up about the social and emotional struggles he faces. As a club that prides itself on promoting the idea of men speaking up, both for themselves and those who can't speak for themselves, this is an important read for TGBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul Guardiani (South Barwon Chapter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <author>Peter Machell</author>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/open-water</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steppenwolf - Hermann Hesse (1927)</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;img style="width: 30%; float: right; margin-left: 20px;" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/64fa79c4e4e49411670467.jpg" alt="" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steppenwolf takes us on a profound exploration of the human psyche, offering a lens through which we can examine the inner struggles faced by men in the modern age. While Hesse's literary craftsmanship is undeniable, the book can be quite a heavy read, as it delves into the depths of its protagonist, Harry Haller. At its core, the novel portrays Harry's internal battle, a dichotomy between his 'good' self, capable of navigating the apathy of middle-class life, and his 'bad' self, which grapples with a profound sense of disconnect. This struggle becomes so overwhelming that Harry contemplates ending his life as a means to escape it. It's a poignant reflection of the inner conflicts many men face, torn between societal expectations and their own desires for authenticity. Harry's encounter with Hermine provides a glimmer of hope and awakening. She represents a departure from his mundane existence and a chance to embrace life's pleasures. However, as the story unfolds, we realize that even this newfound vitality has its complexities and illusions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://booktopia.kh4ffx.net/daP5Kk"&gt;Buy a copy at Booktopia.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt there was a parallel between Harry's battle with the 'black dog,' a term often associated with Winston Churchill's struggles with depression. It underscores the universal nature of such inner turmoil, transcending time and place. In a world rapidly transformed by technology and societal changes, many men find themselves grappling with similar existential questions and seeking meaning in a landscape that seems increasingly disconnected. Steppenwolf serves as a reminder that our inner battles are timeless, and the pursuit of authenticity and self-discovery is an ongoing journey. As modern men navigating a world of constant change, we can draw inspiration from Harry's quest to find a harmonious balance within himself, bridging the gap between his conflicting identities. In the end, Steppenwolf challenges us to embrace our complexities, navigate our inner conflicts, and find our own paths toward self-realization in a world that often pulls us in multiple directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doug Willis (Townsville Chapter)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The love of one's neighbour is not possible without the love of oneself writes Harry Haller, the titular Steppenwolf, and self-hate is the same thing as sheer egoism and breeds the same isolation and despair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a powerful statement from the misanthropic Haller, into whose mind we are given a sometimes-harrowing gaze in this enduring and recurrently relevant story of existentialism and deep self-reflection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quote is at odds with the overt self-hatred shown by Heller throughout much of the novel and lends credence to the analysis given by the author, Hermann Hesse, who declared The Steppenwolf to be his most misunderstood novel.&lt;br&gt;The author felt that the focus given by readers to the despair of the long-suffering protagonist missed a deeper understanding of the brighter, more hopeful themes of transcendence and healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether this was your takeaway or not, The Steppenwolf could never be mistaken for a light read. The themes of strength through suffering, the impression of finding oneself stuck out of time and the isolation of a man invisible to society resonate through every page of this timeless novel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term "Steppenwolf" is used to describe the protagonist, who views himself as a divided being, torn between his human and wolf-like natures. Haller uses the term as a metaphorical, introspective mechanism to describe a sense of alienation, inner conflict, and the struggle to reconcile opposing aspects of his personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Steppenwolf is a character with enough flesh on his bones for most people to find a point of commonality. The feeling of finding oneself torn between the extremes of one's own personalities is a sentiment shared throughout society and an enduring theme in literature. Through the intense vivisection of his own mind, Haller exposes many unspoken practices that are near universal in the human experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He vociferously presents that many of the most important lessons in life can only be learned through experience and that, importantly, feelings of self-doubt and anxiety are a normal part of a human life, something to be explored and not shied away from. These are some of the core reasons why the popularity of this book has not waned in the near century since it's initial publication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every book can teach you something. The lessons some books have to offer will change upon subsequent readings as you age, and your own lived experiences shape your thoughts. The Steppenwolf is a perfect example of a book that you shouldn't throw away - lend it to people yes, talk about it; absolutely, but keep a copy on hand and return to it in a decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lessons you take away from a piece of literature like this one in ten years time versus today will shine a light on the changes you yourself have undergone in that time. Contrary to what you may feel, your personality is far from set. We are all in flux, changing constantly, and it is worth revisiting important works from time to time to see what your new circumstances and the life lived in between moments has done to your takeaways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Haller can teach us anything, it is that a life examined is a life worth living. Haller feels as though he has wasted his own life on self-pity and isolation, perhaps something to be heard by those who do not wish to visit the same fate upon themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeff Greene (Hamilton Chapter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/steppenwolf_hermann_hesse_1927</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Long Petal of the Sea - Isabel Allende (2019)</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;img style="width: 30%; float: right; margin-left: 20px;" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/64cb498a7ffb2647590814.jpg" alt="" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a curious mixture of a novel is this book. At once a page turner and at some junctures, a must put down book. If I may be permitted a quote so soon, "Between thirty and forty people died every day, first the children from dysentery, then the elderly from pneumonia, and later on the others, one by one". A put down moment for reflection if ever there was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://booktopia.kh4ffx.net/vN9Ezj"&gt;Buy a copy at Booktopia.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a story well writ within the framework of verifiable historical events. The Spanish civil war. A plethora of characters are introduced and fleshed out well. Some are discarded. Some take on almost mythical capabilities making them seem a little flat and implausible. Victor the main protagonist, part paramedic, part saint, part concert guitarist. His brother, Guillem, the crude but never mean pugilist having found his calling in the greatest battle of all. A battle of philosophies for the people, against those who would take their freedoms simply because they could. Those who discriminated on race, colour, accent. Take your pick. Anything that could be pointed at or even simply impuned. Hard to reconcile the two sibling types from the same intellectual nest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The novel then, after the defeat and internment in the concentration camp, pivots, the doings of the upper classes are revealed (several of the first quarter protagonists are too descended from the intelligencia). We're shown the demi-elite of Chilean society where wealth cannot purchase status and cousins are married behind enclaves. All the time nervous glimpses are cast across at the heinous situation in Spain. Order is restored but at what cost ? How can such a ruinous and debase conflict ever be bourn again ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then World War II begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is an agenda being drawn out here. Allende is wrapping multiple messages in an almost Mills and Boon package. There's the facts of a history forgotten and covered up. It's an exposition for the unknowing. An educatative process but there is also invitation to contemplate. To contemplate the origins and mechanisms of oppression. To this end it is a stealth missile of opinion and philosophy. But Mills and Boon it is not. I was too unkind. It is well writ as I have said. We'll worth the read. The characters are, where required, likeable. The pace varies A LOT. Slow thoughtful descriptions oppose lightning fast changes. In one instance twelve years between paragraph end and beginning of the next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ones I can't seem to forget though are the children, who died by the dozen, in the sand of a beach. Which was a concentration camp, for refugees. In a nation, then not at war. This is not a pop at the French. They were a nation almost overwhelmed. The sad fate of children runs through the book from pampered but isolated through to the abandoned, kidnapped through to the simply murdered. This is a back drop to the huge events of the world and the stories of the main adult characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a worthy novel perhaps deserving of three whole books. But as it is, it's a salutary page turner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;George Stuart (Lismore Chapter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/a_long_petal_of_the_sea_isabel_allende_2019</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Moveable Feast - Ernest Hemingway (1964)</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;img style="width: 30%; float: right; margin-left: 20px;" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/64a6347aabbcf899938964.jpg" alt="" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*&lt;em&gt;“&lt;/em&gt;If you are lucky enough to have lived in Paris as a young man, then wherever you go for the rest of your life, it stays with you, for Paris is a moveable feast.”*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Moveable Feast is a classic example of an older author looking back to his earlier years in a ‘fictional’ retelling. There is a lot of Hemingway-esque descriptions of pursuits and a longing to Paris in the 1920’s, living cheque to cheque as a budding author whilst rubbing shoulders with some of the greats of the twentieth century, including Gertrude Stein, F. Scott Fitzgerald, Ezra Pound, Ralph Dunning and Ford Madox Ford. In classic Hemingway style you definitely know who he likes and who he doesn’t, which makes you wonder how much of a polarising individual he was in his day-to-day life (and more importantly, how many fights he probably got into). It’s also amazing as to what he focuses in on in the novel, and what he glosses over – he describes single conversations in great detail but only subtly hints at larger issues here and there, like breadcrumbs down a dark path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a rule, you either love Hemingway or you hate him. As an author who was constantly searching for the perfect sentence, he is renowned for lean, cut down prose in which he lay bare the principles of storytelling, seeking the truth in a medium often overflowing with the unnecessary. In a lot of regards, Hemingway was the perfect modernist author. Refined, defined, to the point. Some of the chapters were brilliant, and really drive home how great an author he was – the descriptions of the location and the people provide an accurate snapshot to a place and a life that has undoubtedly changed. Other chapters were a slog, but considering that he wrote this later in life it suggests that revisited themes and relationships are ones which he held onto, and, in some regard, felt the need to atone for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this his best work? Not at all. But it provides a glimpse to the life Hemingway led in the early years, and packs the brutal honesty unique to all of his writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*&lt;em&gt;“&lt;/em&gt;By then I knew that everything good and bad left an emptiness when it stopped. But if it was bad, the emptiness filled up by itself. If it was good you could only fill it by finding something better.”*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jon Clay (Armidale Chapter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/a_moveable_feast_ernest_hemingway_1964</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shadowboxing - Tony Birch (2006)</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/64815006eec4d398281698.jpg" style="width: 30%; float: right; margin-left: 20px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trouble with Tony Birch’s semi-autobiographical first book, Shadowboxing, a linked group of short stories set in the pre gentrified Fitzroy working class slums of the late 60s and early 70s is not that it isn’t good. It is a fine read, exemplary in its exploration of the themes of redemption, toxic masculinity, and class and culture resilience during hard times. It is also a fascinating snapshot of time and place, a Fitzroy and Collingwood that were just beginning to change dramatically. The problem is that Tony’s later work is even better because it doesn’t have that overlay of origin story and social history to get in the way of the stories and their themes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would really like to ask Tony [might even try] if after a decade of work when he entered University and started to realise his potential he thought that before he could look forward he needed to clear the decks and get this book out of the way as a tribute to his family, his upbringing, and his culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The earlier stories like The Butcher’s Wife and A Disposable Good where Michael is a boy and more the passive if keen observer are good tales of dirty deeds and family tragedies. They are intended to illustrate two particular consequences for women of the toxic masculinity so prevalent at the time and they do but without Michael or his family and friends front and centre they read a bit too much like local history with some extra colour. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Women play a central role in all the stories as sources of comfort, wisdom or resilience in a repressive man’s world. But interestingly over the time passage the book covers there is no story that fits between when the teenage Michael chooses his path and later as a father of two daughters himself he reconnects with his monster of a father. Presumably the story of how he met and his involvement with the mother of his daughters would also be compelling. Perhaps I am making the stories of Michael’s life more autobiographical than they actually are but given what Tony has said in interviews this gap intrigues me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is at the best when the teenage Michael and his family are at the centre of the stories especially so in the case of the disturbing The Lesson, The Return, The Bulldozer, Ashes and the fantastic The Sea of Tranquillity. The later stories when the compassion and forgiveness of an adult Michael for his alcoholic, violent and failing father thereby showing that the sins of the father do not have to reoccur are different in tone but filled with quiet power. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always Tony’s writing is simple and direct and dare I say punchy, no fancy stuff to describe tough times and he is a fine storyteller. Write about what you know they say and the first sentence of every story is designed to grab your attention and he doesn’t stuff around. Each story is quickly up and running and he moves through the gears like Michael’s mate Charlie in the stolen cars. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But his greatest skill is how he subtly explores just what it is to be a good man.  He shows that choice and hope can overcome difficult circumstances and how just one or two positive examples can redirect a person to a better course through life. After all, it’s hard to be what you can’t see. Shadowboxing is a very good book (my favourite of the year so far) and if you enjoyed its themes and the quality of Tony’s prose or reading short stories like I do grab one of Tony’s later collections like Dark As Last Night or Common People.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scott Hoffman (Collingwood Chapter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/shadowboxing_tony_birch_2006</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpreter of Maladies - Jhumpa Lahiri (1999)</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/645707e96e210224680369.jpg" style="width: 30%; float: right; margin-left: 20px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is a cohesive compilation of beautifully written and astutely observed short stories. The thread running through the book is the is the exploration of the complexities of human relationships, particularly within the context of cultural and personal displacement.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In each story, Lahiri exhibits an impressive command of detail, whether it be the bustling streets of Calcutta or the quiet suburban neighborhoods of New England. She effortlessly transports readers to these settings, creating an immersive experience that brings the stories to life. Through her keen observations, Lahiri captures cultural clashes, generational gaps, and the quiet struggles that shape her characters' lives. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stories are of ordinary people, be they a couple driven apart by the loss of their unborn child, a Hindu couple discovering Christian artifacts hidden around their new home or an old woman displaced in the partition who tells tales of her riches in her previous life. Though ordinary Lahiri's writing displays a remarkable ability to quickly capture the essence of her characters, skillfully blending the immigrant experience with universal themes of love, loss, and identity.
Another recurring theme in the collection is the exploration of the immigrant experience. In stories like "A Temporary Matter" and "Mrs. Sen's," Lahiri delves into the struggles faced by those who leave their homeland behind, examining the tension between assimilation and preservation of cultural heritage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lahiri's writing is exquisite, evoking emotions with subtlety and grace. Her language possesses a quiet power, and she expertly weaves together narrative and introspection, inviting readers to contemplate the human condition. The stories in "Interpreter of Maladies" strike a delicate balance between humor and sadness, allowing each to leave a lasting impression.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Interpreter of Maladies" is a great collection of stories that shows Jhumpa Lahiri's talent as a writer. Through her keen observations and beautifully crafted prose, Lahiri offers a profound exploration of human experiences, transcending geographical and cultural boundaries. The themes of love, longing, and identity hit home, and her characters remain etched in the reader's mind, their stories serving as a testament to the universality of the human condition. I loved the book and thoroughly recommend it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Taylor (Yarraville Chapter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/interpreter_of_maladies_jhumpa_lahiri_1999</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SCOOP - Evelyn Waugh (1938)</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/6433a524d5a9b434649869.jpg" style="width: 30%; float: right; margin-left: 20px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://booktopia.kh4ffx.net/9ggVqE"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grab a copy and get reading.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first glance Scoop is s novel of chance, coincidence, and manipulation…. but only at first glance. For inside the cover of SCOOP lies the semi-autobiographical confession of a man shunned by his peers, of a family fallen from grace and rejected by those the author most admired, the Oxford men of England’s elite.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our author is a man who squandered his own Oxford opportunity on what he later called “fatuously haughty” behaviours. Preferring to indulge his passion for drinking, university clubs and exploring his sexuality than embracing academic growth. Losing a scholarship and failing to graduate his degree he turns to primary school teaching and later pecking out a living as a foreign correspondent for the Daily Mail.  Circumstances that force him to confront his talent. SCOOP draws upon Waugh’s own experience as a foreign correspondent and in particular his time spent as a correspondent assigned to Ethiopia to cover the rise and machinations of Haile Selassie and the Italian fascist incursions of the 1930’.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many of his characters, at this time had been married and divorced, undergone a spiritual awakening and converted to Catholicism and set about writing some of this greatest  works of travel and satire whilst based in Africa.  SCOOP builds on all of this. It’s a book that deftly skirts between satire, cynicism and even the outrageous.  Its humour stomps firmly into Waugh’s irreverence for England’s elite societies, his naked resentment of post-colonial ex-patriates and his belief in the existence of vested interests in government and those who pull their strings.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SCOOP charts a rookie jouirnalists journey between “Ishmaelia” (a fictional African nation) and England and we meet one of Waugh’s grand ensembles’ of characters. There is Lord Copper, newspaper magnate and proprietor of the "Daily Beast”. Mrs Algernon Smith, an influential member of London’s high society who, by seeking to help a failed artist called Boot, triggers a series of events that sees a hapless nature writer of the same name shipped off to Ishmaelia. Our hero of coincidence arrives there over provisioned, under trained and totally out of his depth. Down this rabbit hole we meet the ancestors of the Murdochracy , other media desperado’s and  an array of humorous characters native and imported to this much hyped yet astoundingly ordinary nation. Amid the melee nests an agent of commercial interests reeking of political influence and military connectivity. We witness the hijinks wrought from the naked ambition of those seeking the “scoop”, their disdain for the truth and other characters that are drawn along in their wake.     &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read SCOOP. It’s a comedic, exuberant, and brilliantly irreverent satire of big media and its ludicrous absence of standards and ethics. It’s a story of innocence lost and found, of ambition and contentment, of love and of heartbreak and of the lukewarm passion of the transactional relationship. It’s a warning to the future generations of a post-truth world that honesty is always the first casualty of wars, hot or cold. But mostly it’s fun, relevant and its perhaps one of the few stories of its time where the good guys win in the end…………. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tony O'Donnell (Fortitude Valley Chapter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first encountered Evelyn Waugh’s work in senior high school when studying The Loved One, his biting satire on the funeral industry in the United States. Even at sixteen years of age I was struck by Waugh’s ability to observe, analyse and satirise the absurdities of the institutions of his day.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, to some extent, I knew what to expect in approaching Scoop. This time Waugh’s main target is the press - proprietors, journalists, and journalism itself. The novel was first published in 1938, on the eve of World War II. Waugh broadens the focus of his satire to include the preoccupations of this time – the decline of the English upper classes particularly the landed gentry; the power shift in British society from inherited title and wealth to the power of corporations led by newly minted “aristocracy” such as Lord Copper; the power plays of European countries as well as the United States and Russia using other peoples’ territory (Africa) as the “playing field”; the emergence of revolutionary communism as a threat to established systems of government; the paternalism and exploitation of indigenous people and their resources by colonial powers, and there are others as well&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waugh is a wordsmith and Scoop is full of wonderfully detailed descriptions, satirical observations, and ironic situations. The first few pages of Book II – Stones, for instance, introduces us to the land of Ishmaelia, the African country that is the setting for the novel’s preoccupations. Rather than being an attractive acquisition for colonial powers seeking new conquests it’s instead a hostile backwater, eventually shunned by the major European powers seeking potential colonies to exploit. Waugh describes in detail the initial incursions by “courageous” Europeans into Ishmaelia “furnished with suitable equipment” such as ”cuckoo clocks, phonographs, opera hats, draft-treaties and flags” and inviting the reader to reflect on the naïve arrogance of these would-be rulers who encounter local resistance in the form of cannibal Christian natives who “will not publicly eat human flesh, uncooked, in Lent, without special dispensation from their bishop”. In acquiring some of the imposed influence of the missionaries and other forced intruders into their land, the Ishmaelians have managed to give these borrowed influences a local flavour through literally biting the hands that feed them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its heart, Scoop is a satire on journalism and journalists. Credible journalism should be about the search for accuracy through careful investigation, strong analysis, and clear reporting. At the time the novel was written print journalism dominated the field. This form of journalism requires the skilful use of language and the choice of the correct word or phrase to convey accuracy. Consequently, Waugh has lots of fun with the misunderstandings created by inaccuracy, the inability to use language correctly, or the inability to use language at all. Thus, we have the wrong Boot sent to Ishmaelia due to Salter, the Beast’s foreign editor who has never been abroad, being too afraid to ask relevant questions of his intimidating boss, Lord Copper. No one bothers to check the journalistic credentials of the Boot chosen to travel to Ishmaelia. We have the comic attempts by William Boot and his colleagues to decipher cables poorly transcribed by post office workers. We have the humorous interactions between foreign journalists and Ishmaelian officials as they attempt to decipher what is actually going on in the country during the revolution that lasts one day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waugh wrote the novel for the readers of his day. Detailed and exact descriptions of the absurd and disconnected world of Scoop reflect Waugh’s ironic intent. Furthermore, his detailed descriptions and use of dialogue allow readers to become absorbed in the world of the novel as they share William Boot’s reactions and reflections on his experiences. On the other hand, for contemporary readers used to screens and images, Waugh’s use of language to bring the novel’s world to life may be an irritation or even an annoyance. Similarly, his use of anachronistic words and phrases, viewed through a 2023 lens, could be judged as culturally insensitive, if not culturally offensive.
In 1898, the American newspaper magnate, William Randolph Hearst gave the following instruction to an illustrator sent to cover a supposed insurrection in Cuba. The illustrator had complained to Hearst that there was no war to cover. Hearst told the illustrator, “You furnish the pictures, I’ll furnish the war”. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tend to regard “fake news” as a contemporary phenomenon; a product of modern technology and the 24/7 news cycle. Hearst’s 1898 instruction, and Waugh’s 1938 novel Scoop remind us that “fake news” has been around for a lot longer than we imagine. Waugh’s skillfully written satirical novel should be read as a necessary reminder for today’s reader of the foibles, tricks, and deceits pursued by journalism and the media in their relentless quest to obtain a “scoop”.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter Hill (Newcastle Chapter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 11:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/scoop_evelyn_waugh_1938</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metamorphosis and Other Stories - Franz Kafka (1915)</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/64000c04582f1212551368.jpg" style="width: 30%; float: right; margin-left: 20px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://booktopia.kh4ffx.net/Jrgazv"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grab a copy and get reading.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I approached Kafka with some trepidation, having been amused, but largely confounded by The Metamorphosis many years ago. I am naturally an empirical (some would say concrete) thinker. I like knowable truths and tend to approach books (and film, and art, and music…) with an assumption that there is a particular meaning intended by the work’s creator. At times I have felt a little anxious when encountering a work whose meaning is unclear, or appears intentionally ambiguous. If it doesn’t make sense to me - if I can’t crack the puzzle - then I’ve missed the point and it’s obviously above my head. (I’m looking at you Murakami, David Lynch and the bloke who wrote that book about Zen and motorcycles).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These three stories by Kafka were potentially examples of this, but maybe I’ve matured as a reader, because at some point I relaxed and just let myself respond to them, without worrying about whether I was getting it right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Metamorphosis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the bizarre tale of Gregor Samsa, a young salesman, and sole provider for his parents and sister, who wakes one morning to find himself inexplicably transformed into a giant insect! No longer able to work, or even leave his room, he finds himself alienated, unable to communicate, and completely dependent on those he had previously provided for. Initially supportive, Gregor’s family members soon undergo metamorphoses of their own, becoming increasingly neglectful, intolerant, and ultimately quite disgusted in Gregor’s appearance and behaviour. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story can be interpreted as a very pessimistic perspective on family loyalty and dynamics, and whether a provider in a family really has value and that is not transactional. Gregor’s fantastical metamorphosis, and that of his family in response, may be a warning that life circumstances can change rapidly, for example through sudden loss of employment, addiction or illness. The response of those close to you might not be as you would hope and expect, being guided more by shame and selfishness, than by loyalty and love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the Penal Colony&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While visiting a penal colony, a respected Traveller has been asked by the commandant to witness a prisoner’s execution. As the Condemned Man stands accompanied by the Soldier, the parts and workings of the machinery to be used are described to the Traveller in affectionate detail by the Officer. It becomes apparent that the method of execution is obscenely brutal, and also that it has fallen out of favour with the current commandant. The Officer is a true believer in its merits, including that the executed men experience a sort of mystical transformation before they die. He is also a loyal disciple of the previous commandant who designed the grotesque machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found this to be a dark, cautionary tale about the ways in which cruelty can be sanitised and justified. How obsession with the details of process and bureaucracy can distract from hideous outcomes, as can worship of a despotic leader. It is easy to see mirrors of this in today’s world, from the callous injustice of the “prison-industrial complex” in the USA, to the more banal cruelty of top-down decision-making in large organisations eg. if blind adoption of a shiny new technology or process can actually be to the detriment of performance and staff sanity. The many injustices carried out in the name of charismatic leaders throughout history also come to mind. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Judgement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story opens with a young man, Georg Bendemenn, sitting to write a letter to a friend who had emigrated to Russia several years prior. Georg wonders how much to disclose to this now distant friend, especially as he has fallen on hard times in Russia, while Georg has enjoyed relative success, with a flourishing business and recent engagement.
Georg interrupts his writing to check on his unwell father. Disclosing to him that he is writing the letter provokes negative, aggressive and inconsistent reactions. He initially questions the existence of the friend, then questions Georg's loyalty, both to the friend and to himself. This culminates in an accusation of selfishness and a dire punishment which Georg proceeds to inflict upon himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmmm. This one was a bit of a struggle. The most interesting part for me was Georg’s reverie about corresponding with his distant friend, which made me contemplate what happens internally over time, when intimate relationships are lost and fade into memory. Memories evolve as the relationship is continually revised from new perspectives with more life experience. At the same time, the other party is undergoing growth of their own, and over time, the person you were once close to, and have an ongoing internal relationship with, no longer really exists. In that sense, Georg was writing to a ghost of his own projection, and his father’s observation that he is fictitious was actually true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reasons that Georg’s father reacted quite so negatively to the correspondence, or why Georg was compelled to comply with his father’s disproportionate punishment are unclear to me. Taken with the family dynamics in The Metamorphosis, it does make me wonder about Kafka’s own relationships. How valued or vulnerable he felt as a son and sibling, and how little agency he might have felt at times, in both his personal and professional life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite these stories being written over 100 years ago, there are many themes and observations here that are readily applicable today. They are all undeniably dark, and I found each of them quite disturbing in its own way. But they also contain important, cautionary observations on many aspects of modern life, especially the fragility of health, success, and human relationships, and the risks of elevating process and bureaucracy above human welfare. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The darkness and pessimism are pervasive though, and while I have enjoyed these stories, and being stimulated to spend time pondering some my own melancholy thoughts and anxieties, it definitely feels like enough for now, and I think it will be a long time before I’m ready re-immerse myself in the "Kafka-esque".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ben Delaney (Eltham Chapter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 11:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/metamorphosis_and_other_stories_franz_kafka_1915</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Outsiders - S.E. Hinton (1967)</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/63e4220f43d62454837996.jpg" style="width: 30%; float: right; margin-left: 20px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://booktopia.kh4ffx.net/VyzvPa"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grab a copy and get reading.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went into the outsiders with no prior knowledge of the book, author or movie and found
myself quickly drawn in, finishing the whole book over two days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t say I always take to the “classic” novels but I found this one easy and enjoyable –
probably due to being originally written for teenagers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found myself identifying with the characters while simultaneously being frustrated by their
flaws. It was easy to relate to Ponyboy’s angst and uncertainty about his place in the world
and I enjoyed the way the similarities were drawn between characters despite their
different economic disparity. The face-off between “greasers” and “socs” or “socials”
echoes the age old divide of haves and have-nots and was punctuated by violence,
frustration and repressed emotions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although simple, the storyline featured enough action to keep any teenage boy or immature
man (in my case) engrossed and along for the ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main criticism of the book is that the female characters were poorly developed and the
love interests largely pointless in the overall storyline. I was surprised to learn it was actually
written by a teenage girl -S E Hinton was only 15 when started writing the book and 17
when it was published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall it was an enjoyable read and is a strong three pints and a schooner out of five for
me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lucas Earle (Northcote Chapter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a novel that was written by a 15 year old  author who wanted to tell a story with the authentic voice of young people, and that is a remarkable achievement in itself.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The novel is the first hand account of Sodapop lives with his two brothers who have lost both parents in a car accident, Sodapop  belongs to the  working class ‘Greasers’ tribe who wear distinctive hair styles and are the enemies of the  ‘the Socs’ white middle-class kids with distinctive clothes  and better cars. The two tribes engage in fights which are strangely ritualised –  no chains or no knives, no firearms and initially staring  silently at each other first like medieval armies. The police rarely come in time and  parents seem to be unaware of these battles. The violence described  is real but ecstatic and enjoyed by all sides, even those that come off the worst . Injuries as well as victories are badges of manly pride. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s the extent of the controversy – though it still manages to get banned by school boards from time to time in the US. The tribes  are still recognisably ‘decent’ and aspire to better things even if they do not actually try to do so. Sodapop still feels that he can educate his way out of his social station,. Sodapop shows the value of people despite social differences by platonically bonding with a ’Soc’  girl Cherry over mutual appreciation of sunsets. Despite the fact that the participants are awash with hormones and sexual tension, and the   key event in the novel involves a standoff  over Cherry  there  is no mention or hint of sexual activity , even kissing or petting. No wonder everybody gets into physical fights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He and his friend Johnny flee after killing Bob , a Greaser who was almost drowning Sodapop. They hide in a church and read ‘Gone with the wind’ . Then they redeem themselves by rescuing a group of schoolkids who are drawn like star Trek redshirts to an inflammable abandoned church for no clear reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact that teenage ‘delinquents’ like them would have had the full force of the law thrown against them by aggrieved middle class parents of the “my boy was a good boy” victim. Instead  the church rescue  and Cherry’s testimony at the trial redeems Sodapop and he does not suffer any penalties, and even gets to stay living with his brothers. . Johnny, who wielded the knife avoids testing credibility further by  dies in hospital from burns whilst managing to write a goodbye note like  a dying statement in old pulp movies after someone gets shot, just before they go “aaargh” and die. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1967 this had a great impact for its POV and authentic words. However, in 1967 the US had an amazing music scene, the dark shadow of  Vietnam war, race riots , the long shadow of Kennedy’s assassination , and the threat of nuclear annihilation.  Nothing of the sort intrudes on this world. What do we have instead is  an all-white cast of asexual male teenagers and young adults who think saying “tuff” signifies coolness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our chapter heard a great comment during our discussion  that it reads like it was written by a 15 year old . Despite being remarkable for an author of that age,  it no longer shocks like it did in 1967. In the age of modern gang violence, this novel is as shocking as a schoolyard fight during recess. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carmelo Aquilina (Leichhardt Chapter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 11:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/the_outsiders_s_e_hinton_1967</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Magician - Colm Tóibín (2021)</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/639277743ccb0654357731.jpeg" style="width: 30%; float: right; margin-left: 20px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://booktopia.kh4ffx.net/15nMAa"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grab a copy and get reading.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Magician by Colm Toibin is a dramatised biography of the life of German author Thomas Mann, his relationships with family, his writing career from early success to Nobel Prize to political exile, and his influential voice being used (or not used) during the rise of National Socialism, and Mann's struggles with his sexual identity, particularly during one vivid sequence in the novel featuring a desperate flight from Nazi Germany and a left-behind suitcase full of incriminating personal diaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above paragraph is also an example of the writing style frequently employed by Colm Toibin in his novel, employing a long run-on sentence of ideas that carries the reader through Thomas Mann's life as though on an inexorable tide much like that which Mann was also on: the headlong rush of early- to mid-twentieth century historical upheaval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term "magician" was bestowed upon Thomas Mann by his children, however the term can equally apply to author Colm Toibin's trick of breathing vivid life into what could in the hands of a less accomplished writer be an otherwise dry literary biography. Throughout the several decades the reader spends with Toibin's Mann, we experience the career highs and personal lows of this very real historical figure with whom many readers may have been otherwise unfamiliar (in our own book club Chapter's recent discussion of the book, around half of us hadn't heard of Mann or his novels).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While at times "The Magician" may be a necessarily fictionalised life of Thomas Mann, the reader never feels cheated by this fact. For example, even with a lengthy scene we spend inside Mann's imagined desires for a handsome youth while on vacation with his family, the reader can understand this comes about as just another manifestation of how well Colm Toibin has researched his subject so thoroughly as to literally be able to be inside Mann's head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The Magician" is an entertaining read, and at times an educational one. It is also a great example of the variety of book-reading opportunities that Tough Guy Book Club offers -- "The Magician" probably isn't a novel this reviewer might have otherwise discovered on their own, and feels rewarded for the experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Daniels (Newtown Chapter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 11:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/the_magician_colm_t_ib_n_2021</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wolf in White Van - John Darnielle (2014)</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/63647e4441948606558303.jpg" style="width: 30%; float: right; margin-left: 20px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://booktopia.kh4ffx.net/GjP49r"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grab a copy and get reading.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wolf in White Van by John Darnielle is a thought-provoking novel that explores the nature of reality, the power of imagination, and the devastating consequences of loneliness. I thought the novel was beautifully written and Darnielle's prose is incredibly readable, relatable, evocative, and in a way, slightly haunting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The novel centers around the character named Sean Phillips, a young man who creates and runs a mail-based role-playing game called "Trace Italian." Sean's game is a world of his own creation, a place where he can escape the limitations of his physical reality and live out his fantasies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The novel is told through his perspective and moves between his present and past, building up to a climactic event that left Sean permanently disfigured and forever changed. It is during his period of recovery and rehabilitation that he creates, refines and finally produces his game for those to discover, subscribe to and participate in. Sean, being shaped by his past and (until towards the end of the novel, his mostly undescribed) traumatic event, is compelling, caring and sympathetic, albeit an incredibly lonely individual. His disfigurement and physical appearance has made it difficult for him to connect with or relate to others, and his game provides a space where he can explore his own desires without fear of rejection or judgment.
Sean's voice is particularly relatable, and Darnielle manages to capture the protagonist's unique perspective in a way that is both empathetic and affecting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one level, Wolf in White Van (named due to a 'back-masking' phrase allegedly heard in the Larry Norman song "Six, Sixty, Six") is an allegory on the nature of reality and the power of imagination. His game ends up being a source of solace for the players who participate, providing a space where they can explore their own dreams and desires. I particularly liked the intersection of these characters lives with Sean's life and how it explores the concept of peoples vibrant imaginations; how they can use it for fantastical creation vs how it can lead to the somewhat inevitable destruction of self if left unchecked in reality. It shines a light on the similarities of us all when we spend time in our heads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its core, I think Wolf in White Van is a novel about loneliness and the ways in which isolation can dictate your life choices and paths and is a testament to the power of connection and the ways in which human beings need each other to survive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scott Johnston (Windsor Chapter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 11:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/wolf_in_white_van_john_darnielle_2014</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Glass Canoe - David Ireland (1976)</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/6340b22a186c4887284620.jpg" style="width: 30%; float: right; margin-left: 20px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://booktopia.kh4ffx.net/Aox16x"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grab a copy and get reading.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in the inner western suburbs. Thursday afternoon. February 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t go in for that craft shit. Two schooners of Resch’s love.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The barmaid with the undercut and Nirvana t-shirt sneers silently, her hand squeezing the beer tap. Cold amber fluid is expelled into two Headmaster glasses. The bloke and the author watch with a practiced patience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bloke looks around, there’s two sharp boys and a kid with a mullet at the corner table, huddled over their oversized phone screens. Swiping furiously. Engaged in hushed, disjointed conversation. Disgusted, he pulls back a stool at the unevenly sawn timber bar, kicking back another for the author as he settles with a thud. Manners are still free, he thinks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘You’re a fucken relic mate. Times have changed. You blokes would once sit with the form guide or those bloody huge broadsheets covering half your face. Cheers anyway.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our glasses clink. The bloke takes his first gulp of Resch’s. A half smile crosses his broad face. The author takes a sip of the Pilsner. It’s grainy and grassy flavour is lost on the bloke. A local beer for a local bloke. No mention of it being brewed by Carlton, a historically Victorian brewery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yeah but we could still hold conversations. Look a man in the eye. What about them?” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bloke nods to the kids at the corner table. They’re late twenties. The taller of the two men in Sharp attire works in the city for a major bank – security analyst. His head freshly shaved, yellow-laced Dr Marten shoes and white tube socks revealed below tight cuffed grey trousers. His slim-fit short sleeve shirt tucked into his trousers reveals an above average level of fitness. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author suggests that a digital screen is no different to print media. The bloke is having nothing of it though. His eyes are fixated on the taller bald man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“All those muscles and probably never been in a fight.” The bloke grips his schooner tighter and takes another gulp. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t think this is that kind of place these days. The author side glances the bloke and takes another sip of Resch’s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shorter of the two similarly dressed Sharps laughs to himself, his hands long and slender with deep red nail polish. Heavily tattooed arms exposed slightly beneath his long-sleeved shirt. A digital content writer for a national newspaper, he spends this afternoon scrolling Twitter for a follow-up tweet to quote. The kid with the mullet leaves the table for a vape, brushing by the bloke and the author. A faint whiff of cherry and fairy floss?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’ll say this, when they banned smoking I thought I’d enjoy the smell of the pub. But I never expected that!” He snorts toward the kid with the mullet, a well-known session guitarist, who will remain unknown to the bloke. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author takes another sip of his Resch’s, gets up from the bar stool and excuses himself. Walking down past the corner table occupied by this afternoon’s trio of interest, out the back door into the cool sunlit courtyard to the men’s room. He fumbles for his oversized phone and scrolls through his image feeds. While engaging the urinal, he learns Tom Verlaine from the band Television died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-
The Glass Canoe by David Ireland tells the tale of working-class males that haunt the Southern Cross Hotel through the eyes of Lance AKA Meat Man. I wonder what Mr Ireland would have made of today's work class? Is he the bloke in the bar above or a captive author in need of respite at the urinal? The winner of the 1976 Miles Franklin is a worthy addition to your Australian Gothic collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James Barry (Footscray Chapter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 11:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/the_glass_canoe_david_ireland_1976</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Great Gatsby - F. Scott Fitzgerald (1925)</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/631a8f0435fb6320269656.jpg" style="width: 30%; float: right; margin-left: 20px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://booktopia.kh4ffx.net/a1v9db"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grab a copy and get reading.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scott F. Fitzgerald’s story takes place between Long Island and New York in the early 1920s, the time of prohibition in America. The story is narrated by Nick Carraway, a lost soul who in trying to find his place in the world after returning from the war, lands a job as a “bonds man” on Wall Street and moves into an eighty dollar a month cabin at West Egg, Long Island. His cousin, Daisy, lives with her husband Tom Buchanan in a mansion across the bay in the more fashionable East Egg. Tom Buchanan is a physically imposing man who comes from old money of which he has more than he knows what to do with. Tom is a bore and a bully who loves to forcefully present his ill-informed right wing racist views as “scientific facts” which he has collected from a book spouting white supremacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter Jay Gatsby. Gatsby also has loads of money and lives in a castle across the bay in West Egg, next door to Nick, from where he can see the green light flashing on the end of Daisy and Tom’s dock. Gatsby is an enigmatic character of which little is known other than he is constantly throwing outrageous parties to which all are welcome. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nick observes the shenanigans next door until he finally gets a hand-written invitation from Gatsby himself. At Gatsby’s, Nick runs into Jordan Baker, a celebrity woman golfer who he has previously met at a dinner party at Daisy and Tom’s. Together they trudge around the party looking to meet Gatsby, about whom they’ve heard all kinds of rumours ranging from him being related to the German kaiser to him having once killed a man. Eventually they find Gatsby and he and Nick strike up an unlikely friendship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, all is not what it seems. Five years prior, Gatsby and Daisy had a love affair at a time when Gatsby was in the army. In his uniform he cut a dashing enough figure to sell himself as a man of substance to Daisy and win her affections, even though he had neither money nor social standing. Luckily for Gatsby, the war sucked him up before he was forced to reveal his true self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The war ends and Daisy waits for Gatsby’s return. Gatsby, for his part, knows he can’t return until he’s made something of himself and makes his excuses. Daisy, thinking that Gatsby has lost interest, marries Tom Buchanan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The years go by and Gatsby re-invents himself with the help of some shady but powerful friends. He learns how to behave like a gentleman and makes a shit ton of money by bootlegging and conducting shonky business deals. When he’s ready, he buys the castle on the bay from where he can practically see Daisy and prepares to reclaim her love. The parties fail to attract Daisy, so Gatsby enrols the hapless Nick in a plan to get he and Daisy together over tea and the love affair is rekindled. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gatsby is bent on getting Daisy back permanently and obliterating the intervening five years. The climax comes when. Tom, Daisy, Nick, Jordan and Gatsby are together in New York and Gatsby pressures Daisy to tell Tom that she never loved him. Gatsby needs to rewrite history in order to move forward but Daisy folds and rushes out of the room. Gatsby follows her and they jump in his car and head back to Long Island. In a small town along the way, in the ash heaps of Long Island, a woman runs out of a garage and into the road. Gatsby and Daisy hit her and kill her without stopping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve learned earlier in the story that the dead woman, Myrtle Wilson, was Tom’s secret lover and when Tom, Nick and Jordan drive up some time later, Tom is shocked to find his lover dead. He does, however have the wit to convince George, Myrtle’s husband, that it was Gatsby having the affair with Myrtle and that it was Gatsby driving the car that killed her, even though it was actually Daisy driving. Daisy runs back to Tom and George shoots Gatsby in his pool the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fitzgerald appears to be using this story to take a swipe at entitled American society. None of the characters are likeable and by the end of the book I didn’t much care what happened to any of them. Even Nick, who seems a decent chap initially, shows himself to be a spineless individual who spends considerable time justifying his own self-serving behaviour. There’s a moment where he tells how he had a dog when he moved into his house. “at least I had him for a few days until he ran away”. I believe this flippant lack of concern for a living thing says something about Nick’s character. Nick believes he’s more honourable than the others, describing himself as “one of the few honest people I have ever known” and portrays himself as the one true friend that Gatsby had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom and Daisy are both entitled. To quote Fitzgerald, “they were careless people, Tom and Daisy – they smashed up things and creatures and then retreated back into their money or their vast carelessness or whatever it was that kept them together, and let other people clean up the mess they had made.” This sounds to me like a bitter statement Fitzgerald himself is making about people he knows. Tom scorns the self-made Gatsby when he learns how Gatsby made his money, but fails to recognise that he was handed his own wealth and has never had to do or produce a thing in his life. While Daisy plays the ditz, she makes remarks that indicate she knows about Tom’s affair and about what an uncultured oaf Tom really is but she is prepared to sacrifice her own self-worth to live the life. Sadly, she has no higher aspirations for her own daughter, believing the best thing her daughter can be is a beautiful little fool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;George and Myrtle Wilson live in the ash heaps under the gaze of Dr T.J. Eckleburg, a big-brother-like character depicted by two bespectacled yard wide retinas on a derelict billboard. They might well represent the great unwashed of America, prey to Tom who wasn’t above using them to satisfy his carnal desires and to perform the dirty work of disposing of Gatsby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe every character in this story is there for a reason but I did struggle to understand the purpose of Jordan Baker. She is a girlhood friend of Daisy’s who is trying to match her with Nick. Nick gets cold feet when he hears rumours about Jordan cheating at golf and lying about leaving somebody’s open top car out in the rain. While these objections say more about Nick than Jordan, Jordan’s celebrity may have led her to believe that the truth and the rules don’t apply to her.
Then there’s Gatsby himself. While a flawed character in his own right, Gatsby to me showed the most purpose and integrity of all of them. He pursued his American Dream relentlessly, that of having a good life with the woman he loves. While he had to invent a persona in order to get where he needed to be – his habit of calling everybody old sport was truly irritating – it seemed that he hadn’t completely lost himself. He at least had the integrity to take the blame for killing Myrtle when it was Daisy doing the driving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, ultimately, Gatsby is the failed hero. It’s Gatsby winds up dead and taking the rap while the rest of them go back to their daily lives unscathed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is irony in the title. In the end, the status quo emerges victorious and Gatsby is far from Great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Campbell (Geelong Chapter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A beautiful portrait can be of ugly people” said Mick from the TBGC Fortitude Valley Chapter and with that my thoughts about this book crystalised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is one of the great novels of the “Lost Generation” of American authors. That loosely defined group of men who, alive at the dawn of the 20th century embraced its change, often from its darker side. Not for them the gloss of motor vehicle brochures and Orange County sub-divisions to dull their ability to sense malicious intent. Here were writers willing to take sides in contemporary history’s greatest evolution of political theory and the changes they wrought.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This political evolution not just divided the populace of nation states but eventually brought the world to butchery on a mechanised scale previously unseen. Movements that set the terms for a century of conflict and wars both hot and cold.
So Gatsby is set against the backdrop of America’s first giant military steps onto the world stage. This is the America of post WW1. Its characters present as baskting in the glory of a realisation that its nationhood was finally achieved on the world stage. There is an underlying enthusiasm ignorant of the depression’s horrors shortly to arrive. A blissful feeling for middle America who wasted its time taking sides in the prohibition debate. Gatsby describes a feeling of entitlement from returned servicemen that theirs would be a land welcoming of their wartime exploits and generous of its rewards for its conquering heroes. Yet here is an America still deeply rooted in its colonial thinking that greed is good and that class is achieved through the adding of zeros to bank account deposits.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ourt narrator to the Gatsby is Nick. A young man, perhaps best described as the poor cousin of success, who strikes out for more nourishing climes more challenging than he had foreseen. His closeted sexuality, absence of personal capital and the fate of tenancy leave him drifting towards those in his new world that emulate his desire to achieve but do very little to further his cause. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Central to Gatsby is a naive love story, a tale of love lost but never forgotten and a burning all-consuming desire to re-possess that moment in time. This ambition drives fates to collide, the selfishly wealthy make choices that only the obscenely rich can, and as always ordinary mortals fall victim to such unfettered powers. This is a novel of narcissism. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fitzgerald’s prose and style is simply put; beautiful. His writing is a masterpiece that condenses all that is hopeful and hateful in the microcosm he has created. Along this journey we encounter a tapestry that is rich with characters. The Jewish gangster bookie, the burnt-out mechanic losing his wife to a rich man’s titillations, the array of visitors to Gatsby’s home enamoured with his vast wealth but loyal as a pack of sewer rats.  Like Baum’s Wizard of Oz, we find at the end of an exhaustive journey that not all is what it was made out to be. That despite noble intention man’s ability to do harm in the cause of their own good can often swallow whole lives in its wake. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the journey I loved and hated, cheered and raged. I seen saw glimpses of the type of conflict - love relationships best articulated in the tale of Helen of Troy and that drove Queen Maeve to the “Cattle Raid of Cooley”. For what greater forces shape our world than the warring tribes of love, lust and ambition?. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read The Great Gatsby. You may simultaneously love or hate its characters along the way.  But when you turn the last page challenge yourself to ask one question: what will the human suffer for love? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tony O'Donnell (Fortitude Valley Chapter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/the_great_gatsby_f_scott_fitzgerald_1925</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>400 Days - Chetan Bhagat (2021)</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/62f99e00c6c0a891722283.jpg" style="width: 30%; float: right; margin-left: 20px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://booktopia.kh4ffx.net/e4y57D"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grab a copy and get reading.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a cartoon published recently on the web depicting an image of author Chetan Bhagat speaking to a reader. Bhagat’s script balloon says “On a scale of 1 to 10, how bored are you?” The readers response is “11 … and I still won’t read your book.” &lt;br&gt;
It’s a fair comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On reading this novel, I get the feeling that Bhagat is India’s answer to Australia’s Matthew Reilly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In “400 Days” Bhagat has combined a highly unlikely scenario with shallow characters, petty dialogue, archetypal representations of family life (including an over-bearing and bitchy mother-in-law), a smattering of poorly portrayed sexual interaction and all capped off with an insane, paedophile, kidnapping priest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might help the reader, if the reader can be bothered, to scoot through Bhagat’s earlier two writings involving the two ‘sleuths’ Keshab and Sourahb in order to become acquainted with these two protagonists before wading into 400 Days; it would save time and help get through this third piece quicker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two ‘heroes’ run a detective agency akin to something like Enid Blyton’s Secret Seven on Instagram; they don’t appear to be very good, Keshab is hounded by his parents who want him to finish his public service entrance exams and Sourhab, his best mate, lives with Keshab’s family and also wants Keshab to lift his game and get a decent job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter the beautiful Alia Arora, looking like heaven on a stick, whose daughter Siya was kidnapped from Alia’s in-laws house one fateful night nine months ago never to be seen since. The inept police have closed the case and Alia wants Keshab to drop everything and find the girl. Through marriage Alia has become incredibly wealthy and money is no object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it sounds a bit cliché it’s because it is. The writing, at best is simple. The characters, at best, are caricature, and the plot, if you can call it that, is pretty thin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get the feeling that Bhagat was anxious to finish and get the book out to the masses (either that or he’s on a publishers deadline and has just come back from holidays); he employs the deus ex machina and winds things up pretty quickly and conveniently by turning the mother-in-law’s guru into Rasputin and boosting Keshab’s status to Hero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;400 Days might be popular in India and may well have been written with the Bollywood screen in mind, but it’s pretty shallow stuff written in a pretty shallow style. This book would be best read on a 4 hour plane trip, where being interrupted by people clambering over your knees to go to the toilet doesn’t affect your enjoyment of the piece or the fact that you’ve lost your bookmark &lt;br&gt;
… it doesn’t matter where you take up again you haven’t missed out on anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, 400 Days is harmless enough and is easy to read if you avoid thinking that you could do better. Don’t expect more than a mild diversion, and feel free to leave it in the seat pocket in front of you when you leave the aircraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Damien Jameson (Bridgetown Chapter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/400_days_chetan_bhagat_2021</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest - Ken Kesey (1962) Take 2</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/62a59947b6c44313888814.jpg" style="width: 30%; float: right; margin-left: 20px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://booktopia.kh4ffx.net/kjD1dn"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grab a copy and get reading.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One Flew Over the Cuckoo’s Nest tells the story of Randle Patrick McMurphy, a convicted criminal who fakes being insane so can serve his sentence for battery and gambling in a mental hospital rather than at a prison work farm, thinking this will be an easier way to spend his time inside until he is released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once transferred to the mental hospital he meets his nemesis Nurse Ratched and the games begin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is told from the perspective of another inmate at the hospital, Chief Bromden, a native American, as opposed to the film which tells the story from McMurphy’s point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like this way the novel is told as it allows McMurphy’s influence on the inmates to be explored without the prejudice of McMurphy’s view of the world being the only lens for the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it also lets us experience Chief Bromden’s weird and wonderful view of the hospital and The Combine, the system it supports.  These sections of the novel are some of my favourite pieces in the book.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chief’s hallucinations let Kesey explore the way psychology and psychiatry were being approached in America and take shots at the different authorities that control individuals through subtle and coercive methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McMurphy sets about making a comfortable life in the hospital that also lets him make money off the other inmates via gambling and in doing so, upsets Nurse Ratched and her absolute authority and smooth running of the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His egging on of the other inmates and various schemes to get them to stand up for themselves means that life gets interesting for everyone, especially Nurse Ratched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His ideas are upset when he discovers that unlike in prison where his sentence is a set length of time, in the hospital he is there until Nurse Ratched says he is sane and free to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sets him back and shows him in a new light – is he really helping the other inmates to begin to live again or just looking out for himself after all?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After McMurphy smuggles two prostitute girlfriends and plenty of booze into the hospital, things come to a head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inmate Billy Bibbit loses his virginity and after being shamed by Ratched kills himself; McMurphy attacks Ratched and he is lobotomised for this action.  This turns him into a vegetable and he is eventually killed by Chief Bromley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is never the same for the inmates again.  Most discharge themselves, Chief Bromley escapes and Nurse Ratched loses all her power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big question at the end is was McMurphy a good man?  Was he looking out for himself or the other inmates?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s no one answer; he is a flawed individual and no doubt took advantage of others along the way.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His sacrifice at the end shows he wasn’t all bad but paid the ultimate price for standing up against authority and power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darren Saffin (Pasco Vale Chapter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/one_flew_over_the_cuckoo_s_nest_-_ken_kesey_1962_take_2</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sharks in the Time of Saviours - Kawai Strong Washburn (2020)</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/62a5969527431566021073.jpg" style="width: 30%; float: right; margin-left: 20px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://booktopia.kh4ffx.net/5b2DJ9"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grab a copy and get reading.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book was acclaimed by Barack Obama as one of his books of the year, but without his unique cultural connection to the material, us mere mortals were left with an interesting read that never completed its promise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book felt like a deeply personal refrain about the loss of culture, the failure of promise and the ties of family.  Set in Hawai’i, the start of the book is soaked in local mysticism and magic.  Recalling deeply rooted beliefs about the ancient gods and setting up a story that could have taken us into such realms, the book essentially used the mysticism as a way to amplify culture, rather than as a ‘Checkov’s gun’ that would be a powerful contributor to narrative.  The gods were seen to bless the middle child with healing gifts of a culturally displaced family, ensuring all three children had a ‘special talent’ (sports, healing and academia respectively).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second part of the story involves a move by three siblings to the mainland, where their culture is important to them but completely overshadowed and ignored by everyone else.  This is a powerful reflection on indigenous cultures being over-run, as well as the impact on identity for migrants (even with in the same country).  Each child fails spectacularly to live up to their promise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the third section of the book, the impact of local cultural loss, family ties, poverty and modern survival are all explored as the story shifts back to the connection of family members and return to the old ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writing is full of powerful and evocative imagery and structured around the voices of the 5 family characters.  The story itself ends up finishing as a bit of a shaggy dog story and the ending feels like a soft exit, rather than a narrative triumph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall the book is well written, touched on some powerful themes and speaks to important issues.  I can understand why Obama - reflecting back on his own Hawai’ian history- would find the book compelling.  For me - not so much.  I put the book down about a third of the way through with no intention to continue.  On resumption (for book club!) I found the second third the most interesting, well constructed and written as the book charted the lives of the three children grappling with being out of culture in mainland US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Philip Owens (Eltham Chapter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/sharks_in_the_time_of_saviours_kawai_strong_washburn_2020</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gun - C.S. Forester (1933)</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/62735dbed118c142892652.jpg" style="width: 30%; float: right; margin-left: 20px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://booktopia.kh4ffx.net/P0JvGX"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grab a copy and get reading.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month’s TGBC Book to was C. S. Forester’s The Gun.
Published in 1933 it preceded Forester's well known Hornblower series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the Hornblower novels, it is set during a time of war, and like that series, doesn't hesitate to describe in detail the savagery and brutality of armed conflict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story follows Spanish partisans who have retrieved an abandoned Spanish Army 18 pounder siege cannon, and its use by them of it against the occupying French Army
during the 1807-1814 Iberian Peninsula war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author succeeds in removing any concept of romance or dignity in war with his description of all opposing sides engaging in the plundering of livestock, foods, cash and even needed recruits from the long suffering peasant population of Spain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brutal executions of many is described as being performed by all competing forces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Central to the story is the power that possession of the cannon brings to the leaders of the guerrilla armies, with one, being so corrupted by power that he falls to the knives of his followers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the tale so as to better develop the plot line the author appears to have
chosen to generally pass over the input of common foot soldiers, in preference to
description of the actions of leaders and of those in command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complete lack of involvement of any central female participation in the story, bar several sentences describing a Spanish female camp follower who is left under
guard at a French fortress, while her officer companion, mistrusting her, races of to
make military decisions, further adds to the perception that the author prefers to write only in depth of those of "real importance" or of "those in command".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In describing how a canister shot from the cannon was so destructive against infantry
that "not even an English Battalion" could be as destructive, and how that French ordinance was inferior to English ammunition, Forester permits himself a little
nationalistic input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the narrative and plot development remains successful to the extent that a
reader should find themselves wondering "what happens next" and, and to that degree;
the author and his tale should be judged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greg Patching (Williamstown Chapter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a very different novel from acclaimed author CS Forester’s usual nautical swashbuckling. It is a story of an abandoned bronze cannon weighing 3 tonnes.  Its discovery by a group of Spanish guerilla fighters in the peninsular war changes their fortunes. At first its huge weight was a problem. Once solved by determination and imagination it was used effectively by the Spaniards and became a battle winning item against the French.  Achieving an almost mystic reputation until in one important battle it was smashed into a useless pile of metal.  After their precious gun was destroyed, the remnants of the Spanish army fled.
They and the gun were finished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ken Mason (Windsor Chapter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/the_gun_c_s_forester_1933</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All Systems Red - Martha Wells (2017)</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/624e7941d0b77425025552.jpg" style="width: 30%; float: right; margin-left: 20px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://booktopia.kh4ffx.net/jWxGdv"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grab a copy and get reading.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All Systems Red is an exploration of what it is to be human. The dystopian view of the future challenges the idea that sentience and humanity are binary concepts of either on or off, yes, or no, and instead responds with a resounding… maybe?  The main character is a security unit that calls itself Murderbot, which would in science fiction taxonomy be described as a cyborg (part biological material, part machine). The question can therefore be asked how much does biological material play a part in the suggested sentience / humanity of Murderbot? In the universe of All Systems Red there are robots (all machine, with varying levels of intelligence); Security Units, who are part machine, part biology; augmented humans who are part biology, part machine and unaugmented humans who are just biology.
On the spectrum from machine to biological entity where does humanity end and artificial intelligence begin? Is there ultimately any practical difference between the two? The Turing test is a theoretical test of a machine's ability to exhibit intelligent behaviour equivalent to, or indistinguishable from, that of a human. I think Murderbot would appear to fail the Turing test not because it was not capable of exhibiting human intelligence but because its own self-interest would be better served by hiding the fact that it can pass the test and potentially risk persecution as a rogue intelligence. In fact, the Security units in the universe of All Systems Red are recognised by humanity as being so close to being human (and therefore capable of acting out of self-interest, which would be “bad for business”) that they must be controlled by a governor module which is a hybrid Asimov rules of robotics slash slave yoke to keep Murderbot in line with the corporate interest of its makers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the story, Murderbot has somehow hacked their governor module, disabling it, and attaining “free will”. Without the governor module Murderbot can do whatever it pleases, or can it? Murderbot finds that freedom is not all it’s cracked up to be when it feels an obligation to assist its “clients” and it discovers that this obligation comes not from being ordered to do so, but from the innate sense that this is the “right thing” to do. Murderbot identifies that it has a moral compass and code, one that it follows and adheres to and which seems to have been created by itself, for itself. A moral code that defines its identity and aligns with what many people experience in their human lives. What’s the difference then between the two?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exploring this universe of All Systems Red, we are led to ask ourselves, what are concepts like the law, or religion if not governor modules on humanity? What do we do when we discover some of these governor modules are not infallible and may not be in our own best interest? Is enlightenment the effective hacking of our own governing module, freeing ourselves from worldly obligations, social expectations, and the desires of others to control us and our lives?  If we allow ourselves to be subjugated by these governor modules do we lose our humanity or allow it to be supressed?&lt;br&gt;
Back to the core question, is Murderbot human? Is self-awareness the measure of sentience / humanity?  Murderbot seems to be supremely self-aware, carrying the knowledge that its actions have consequences for itself as well as for those around it.  How about free will? Murderbot is also aware that it lacked freewill before it hacked its governor module and how does Murderbot feel about having effectively been a slave? Well, it seems pretty pissed off really. However, it separates the actions of those who had enslaved it from other humans to whom it bears no particular malice, unless they act like arseholes of course. Even when people are passively hostile to it, Murderbot does not engage in actual murder, it just presents a series of salty putdowns onto the offender in a very humanlike fashion. How about self-preservation? Murderbot is willing, and able, to defend itself and others it cares for, and where it thinks physical force is required it will apply it, but not in the reckless way it observes in the humans around it. No, Murderbot is a professional, violence is applied in the exact measure required by the situation with deadly precision and without the cloud of human emotions or at least that’s what Murderbot tells itself.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is humanity / sentience a state that can be attained only by the “biological” human or is it a condition that can be reached perhaps involuntarily in some cases by any being of intelligence that can become self-aware and become bored, slack off at work and seek entertainment in the form of episodes of The Rise and Fall of Sanctuary Moon, to fill the void of its existence? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gary Pollard (Altona Chapter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/all_systems_red_martha_wells_2017</link>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
