<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>News - Tough Guy Book Club</title>
    <description/>
    <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/news</link>
    <item>
      <title>TGBC Monthly Challenge - #RedSugar</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Each month the Tough Guy Book Club issues a challenge to all members. Some challenges are fun, some are creative, others are health-related – those ones are bloody important and can be lifesaving! In October all goons were tasked to go out and get their blood sugar checked – a screen for diabetes. They had to get a photo and put it on our socials with the hashtag #RedSugar.  One person is diagnosed with diabetes every five minutes in Australia, and 2.6 people a minute in USA. It leads to all sorts of health problems, but if you catch it early (as at least one goon did this month) it can be managed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was great to see so many goons posting their results. A visit to the pharmacist for a finger prick and reading will give you a quick result – once the dispenser had figured out the instructions, apparently not a regular request in some places unfortunately. Otherwise, a blood test can be requested from your doctor and is a good way to carry out a full check-up. Some were assessed as low risk and advised a test wasn’t required – that’s cool too, the question was asked, and the risk assessed buy a professional. Some goons have been living with diabetes, type 1, or type 2, for some time - a convenient challenge for them as they have the kit at home and know their numbers very well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diabetes Australia states that, for a person without diabetes, the day Blood Glucose Levels (BGLs) will generally range between 4.0 – 7.8 millimoles of glucose per litre of blood (mmols/L) and there were a lot of photos of goons with readings within that range. For at least one goon the results were well outside the normal range, raising alarm bells and prompting action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Josh Hayward from the Altona chapter had an initial reading of 13 mmol/L which was a massive red flag. “After the initial result I immediately booked an appointment with the doctor and had several readings hovering around ten,” Josh said. This led to many tests and appointments ultimately resulting in a diagnosis of type 1 diabetes, which was a bloody big surprise. “I am 33 years old and generally quite well. I went into this challenge with ZERO inkling that anything was wrong with my health.” If type 1 diabetes remains undiagnosed it can lead to diabetic ketoacidosis, a life-threatening medical emergency (information from Diabetes Australia), but if caught early it can be managed. “Purely because of the #RedSugar challenge we found the diagnosis early in my journey, and now it is something I need to manage for the rest of my life,” said Josh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That rest of life management looks tough: continuously monitoring blood glucose levels, injecting himself with insulin before each meal, tweaking doses to match carb intake, and staying on top of other key areas of health that are most likely affected by diabetes – linking up with optometrists and podiatrists. “There's a lot to learn very quickly,” Josh related, “but I'm surrounded by amazing support both from the health system and my wife and broader family, so I'm starting the journey optimistic that I can get along just fine for a long time yet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is one thing to say about the ordeal it is to get out and do the challenges! Josh has completed almost every challenge since he joined TGBC in June 2022, and if he hadn’t participated in #RedSugar he could have remained unmanaged long enough to have a potentially nasty health crisis. The challenges can be a fun way to connect with the club, but as you can see, they can be a whole lot more important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do the challenges, get your check-ups, and stay safe!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://assets.nationbuilder.com/tgbc/pages/325/attachments/original/1704254189/_redsugar.jpg?1704254189" alt="" width="945" height="799"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 14:49:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/tgbc_redsugar</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goon Profile - Thomas Giles</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 Thomas Giles&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 Gold Coast Chapter - President &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who are you:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 I’m 36 and still don't know for sure. Son, Brother, Father, Punk Rock Warlord. Protector of the principles of science and logic. Cricket tragic and closet Pyromaniac.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How long have you been with TGBC:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 6 years&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you end up coming to TGBC:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 Lifelong friend and Footscray chapter president James Barry spoke of the glorious times had at TGBC. A wonderful evening spent with Shay and James at Bar Josephine's 2 years ago made it an easy choice. I have cursed James’s name many times for bringing me to this club and forcing me to be a better person. Life is better with the TGBC.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s your favourite TGBC book?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;
 The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why are you a member of TGBC:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;
 It is in the blood now, and the skin. Evolution and growth of the mind and soul.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What book have we not read yet that you’d like to do at TGBC:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;
 South by Ernest Shackleton - the greatest adventure I have ever read about. Whenever I am in a tough spot I think it has to be better than rowing across the southern ocean in a 4 metre tinnie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="featured-images text-center"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
 &lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/61075759e9bee439512019.jpg" style="max-width: 100%" /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/goon_profile_thomas_giles</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TGBC Monthly Challenge - #StraightArms</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tough Guy Book Club is more than just a bunch of guys meeting at the pub once a month. We do a lot of other stuff outside of chapter meetings of course, and one of those things is our monthly challenge. But, since we are a book club that meets at the pub, sometimes it’s good to make sure to get outside to do something other than just bending elbows. That’s why the challenge for May was straight arms.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The straight arms challenge instructed Goons to do something together without alcohol then chuck a photo in our Facebook group with the hashtag #straightarms. Goons could do anything they wanted, just with no booze allowed. Take a walk, kick a ball, look at the ocean, hell, have a cup of coffee. Just do something without drinking.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;In a society that uses alcohol as a social lubricant, especially for guys, it can feel weird inviting another man out for an activity that isn’t going to the pub. But that’s kind of the point of the challenge. Get out of the comfort zone a little bit while also giving the liver a day off.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;At our core, we’re still a book club that meets at the pub. That’s fun. We all enjoy it. We like having a couple beers and talking loudly about books. In fact, we’re damn good at it. But doing stuff outside of the pub was a good way to find out what else we’re all good at.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;And the @straightarms challenge saw some tough stuff happening between Goons. Groups of Goons were seen on bikes, on the golf course, or just taking over their local coffee shop or walking trail. Some Goons broke out the instruments and had a jam, others braved the Autumn weather at the beach. TGBC members get creative when they’re not allowed to go to the pub. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;In typical Tough Guy fashion, some of the guys decided to combine the #straightarms challenge with doing a good thing. We had some guys donating blood together and others teaming up to help with another’s grandmother’s garden. Not a bad effort at all.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Although it was #straightarms month, plenty of club members still got together for a beer or two as well. There’s nothing wrong with hitting the pub with your mates. But the #straightarms challenge also helps everyone remember there are things to do with guys other than the pub. The challenge was also a good opportunity to make friends outside of the regular chapter meeting. Yeah, talking books is great, but a lot of Goons start going to club to make new friends. We’re all busy, so it’s hard to find an excuse to meet up outside of the regular meetings. Sometimes you need an excuse like the monthly challenge to force you to meet up.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Getting involved in the TGBC monthly challenge is always a little bit different, a bunch of fun, and also pretty rewarding. We announce the challenge at chapter meetings and then again on Facebook a couple days after. Be sure to pay attention and get involved in the next one.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remember you can’t read a book if you’ve had too many, drink responsibly or else.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="featured-images text-center"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
 &lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/64ddc09c4fa2b686416501.png" style="max-width: 100%" /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/tgbc_monthly_challenge_straightarms</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TGBC MONTHLY CHALLENGE - #ReadthePlaques</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glossy metal - usually brass, aluminium or similar. Most often rectangular and, if so, about A5 in size. Other shapes, too, but – ironically - rarely large enough to attract attention.
 Plaques.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;They occupy corners in communities and hearts across the country. At the same time, however, their familiarity can breed indifference and even contempt. Their purpose at the time of laying is rarely questioned, but years pass and attitudes change. Some plaques and the people, the events and landmarks they commemorate retain the reverence with which they were unveiled. Others much less so, becoming nagging reminders of the embarrassing, the ugly and the odious in our past.
 The #readtheplaque challenge had goons sharing photos of plaques from all points of the compass. In doing so, they shared glimpses of history from their part of the world. Some goons, it seems, had a go-to plaque, while others found themselves truly challenged and needing to hit the street in search of plaque prey. If there was a rise in the number of injuries to pedestrians nationwide coinciding with this challenge, it was likely due to goons looking left and right rather than straight ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;So what was unearthed?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The poignant. Like the ‘Blacksmith’s Tree’ at Strathewen Community Bushfire Memorial for those lost to, and those who fought, the Black Saturday fires in 2009. The despair that gripped the nation throughout those dark days won’t soon be forgotten, but who knew that blacksmiths from across the world would come together and gift the local community amazing art in a wonderful act of compassion? &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Picture1.png" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/64e6bb8f29a2f676672968.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The sad. The good old days weren’t always that good. This plaque marks the burial site of 33 of the 96 men and boys killed in Australia’s worst ever workplace accident, a Mount Kembla mine explosion. May they rest in peace.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Picture2.png" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/64e6bbc130d56155408458.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The downright depressing. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Picture3.png" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/64e6bbd375d52751915564.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Boab Prison Tree serves as a powerful reminder of a shameful chapter in Australian history. Say what you want about the Voice to Parliament, past injustices against Australia’s first peoples cannot be wished away.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The uplifting. Surfers’ Paradise offered up its ‘Matey’ plaque. And why shouldn’t we simultaneously celebrate a homeless but beloved canine, acknowledge another’s sacrifice and fundraise for animal welfare? &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Picture4.png" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/64e6bbeee13bd727421318.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The just. Trailblazers are widely memorialized through the laying of plaques and more often than not, those trailblazers were men. Excellent, then, that The Royal Melbourne Hospital should give a well-deserved nod to women in medicine. Well done, them.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Picture5.png" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/64e6bbf9573e8027500948.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;And honourable mention to the funny. ‘Shoes on wire’ speaks for itself! We’ve all seen shoes dangling over power lines; suburbia just wouldn’t be suburbia without them. While there are competing theories as to their meaning (and that’s a whole other story, already penned for posterity), one has to question how many of them have been immortalised in plaque form.
 Challenge accepted. Challenge completed.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Picture6.png" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/64e6bc1ce3c6a422345924.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="featured-images text-center"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
 &lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/64e6bd1e3e1e4808111725.jpg" style="max-width: 100%" /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/tgbc_monthly_challenge_readtheplaques</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TGBC Monthly Challenge - #ThugLife</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know there are places in your community that provide a safe place out of the elements for you to read, use a computer, have meetings, make a podcast, provide activities for kids, and are staffed by learned superheros who just go out of their way help? Also, they let you borrow heaps of books from a massive selection and trust you to take them to your house to read – for free! &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;I don’t think I need to convert many readers here to the view that libraries are fucking amazing places. Each month Tough Guy Book Club sets a challenge to all members, daring them to do something fun, different, difficult, or random. This month it was for everyone to visit their local library and snap a photo to share with the tag #ThugLife. Why Thug Life? Because libraries are cool as shit.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The goons turned out in huge numbers. Some snapped a pic on their regular weekly visits, treading well-worn paths and quipping with their favourite librarians. Others renewed lapsed membership cards and rekindled an old relationship with their community book hub. Some joined up as a new member, the first time back in a library since school and were, I can only imagine, awed by the experience, and converted to a life of whispered wonder.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The range of libraries that we got to glimpse from the shared photos was great to see. From tiny out post huts servicing small communities, to grand state libraries showcasing the beauty of book and architecture. Modern glass and concrete construction, to flaky paint throwbacks to another time. There are un-staffed libraries that heighten the trust, allowing you to enter by scanning your card. And even a library with a rooftop bar – fitting in very well with our values of combining books with a beer.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Some went in groups, sharing the experience with other goons for a catch up outside club night. Many were proud to show the fruits of their visit, with an old favourite being borrowed or an unexpected find. Tips were shared to get the most out of the services offered, with references to free audiobooks, e-books, movie selections, and even tool libraries – which are another level of cool. It was also wonderful to see the number of guys with their kids, visiting the children’s section and fostering the love of books in the next generation.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Let’s continue the challenge. Libraries are important. They are critical pieces of infrastructure in our community. Beyond the obvious services offered they are also; safe spaces for those in need, warm places for those with nowhere to go, offer access to ideas to those who want to learn even if blocked by other means and a just fun places to spend time. Libraries won’t get worn out by overuse, they will only get stronger – with more resources and budget allocated the more they are used.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Get to a library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="featured-images text-center"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
 &lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/64ddc0749ac49384370109.png" style="max-width: 100%" /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 11:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/tgbc_monthly_challenge_thuglife</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Camp of the River Lizard</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Another year, another great TGBC camp.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;While a lot of Goons like to write, more of us are readers, so we figured we’d heavily modify a famous work to get across exactly how awesome camp is:&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;It was the best of times, it was the &lt;s&gt;worst&lt;/s&gt; best of times, it was the age of wisdom, it was the age of foolishness, it was the epoch of &lt;s&gt;belief&lt;/s&gt; fun, it was the epoch of &lt;s&gt;incredulity&lt;/s&gt; mateship, it was the season of Light during the day, it was &lt;s&gt;the season of Darkness at night, it was the spring of hope, it was the winter of despair&lt;/s&gt; late summer in Gippsland, we had everything before us, &lt;s&gt;we had nothing before us&lt;/s&gt; and lots of activities, we were all going direct to Heaven, those who played Liar’s Dice we were all going direct the other way—in short, &lt;s&gt;the period was so far like the present period, that some of its noisiest authorities insisted on its being received, for good or for evil, in the superlative degree of comparison only&lt;/s&gt; it was a great bloody camp.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;If the fact that we’re willing to ruin Dickens doesn’t convey the sheer brilliance of camp, then nothing really will. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But to go into more detail, TGBC had another successful camp.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This was our third camp in just over 12 months since we’re moving the event to be in late Summer rather than late Winter. All in all this is a better format. Plus it allows us to continue to use the wonderful Licola Wilderness Village in North Gippsland.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;So this was our second time at Licola and, unsurprisingly, it was as damn good as the first time. Some things changed from the first time, some stayed the same.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What changed?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The weather for one thing. Last year the rain didn’t stop us from having fun, but the Camp of the River Lizard brought nothing but sunshine for (almost) the entire weekend. This allowed for a lot more outdoor activities including archery lessons, more hiking, and even a river regatta with inflatable pool toys.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Words do not do the regatta justice, so we’ll let the pictures in this article tell the story.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What changed a little?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Nicer weather meant more time with what is quickly becoming a camp tradition: the giant slip and slide. Licola Wilderness Village has a small hill leading to their oval which is perfect for a big sheet of plastic covered in soap and water. And that had Goons flying down it at great speeds. Surprisingly, there were no serious injuries this year, other than some temporary blindness from the soap. We all walked away from that one with slightly redder eyes but having had a whole lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What stayed the same?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Of course camp always has the same fun aspects of bonding with mates, singalongs, and a couple of beers, but it was good to see a lot of the familiar favourites that Goons have come to expect at camp.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One tradition of camp is Book Club. At the core of everything we are a book club afterall. While we all go to our separate chapters every month, camp is a good time to sit down with Goons you don’t usually sit down with and discuss some writing. Things are a bit different at camp: we read and discuss a short story instead of a full book. This year we read “The Drover’s Wife” by Henry Lawson. We won’t go into the story (read it yourself), but, as predicted, Goons did what they did best and had a good chat about prose. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Another tradition, Liar’s Dice, led to a few sore heads on the last morning of camp. This game involves rolling dice and bluffing on your score (and the unknown score of other players). If you’re caught in your bluff, you drink. If a person calls a bluff but it turns out they’re wrong, they drink. It’s a fun tradition at camp, but one that can be difficult for newcomers.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;What also stayed the same is every Goon doing their bit. We appreciate that we take over a wonderful wilderness camp for three days. We spread out with our axe throwing range, giant marquee, a campfire, and more. However, we always lean back on our biggest rule: don’t be a fuckhead. Sure, by the end of the weekend there’s a bit of a clean up, but with everyone pitching in all the garbage is taken out, the marquee taken down, and everything clean very quickly. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;And because of that we’ll be back at Licola next year. They do a good job at Licola Wilderness Village, and we look forward to many more camps for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="featured-images text-center"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
 &lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/64100f0763008455961970.jpg" style="max-width: 100%" /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 11:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/camp_of_the_river_lizard</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TGBC Monthly Challenge - #BPTest</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;105/75mmHg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;See that? That's a blood pressure reading. The first number is systolic pressure, which is the level of pressure against your artery walls when your heart beats. The second number is diastolic pressure, which is the level of pressure between beats when your heart rests. The 'mmHg' means millimetres of mercury. It's one of those weird medical things where the old machines used mercury even though the new ones don't. The old machine is called a sphygmomanometer, which is a great word. Definitely finding excuses to say that more often.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tough Guy Book Club's challenge for February 2023 is to get your blood pressure checked.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Look, we've done this before. It's not new or sexy or especially interesting compared to some other challenges, but it is important. And a lot of goons - busy being stubborn or easily distracted modern men - forget to do it. Even though it's really easy. You can do it with your GP, at most pharmacies, or you can play around with the machine your mate has at home. And it's such a good way to get a read on your health.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We've had dudes do this challenge, get sent straight to the emergency department and start medication by the end of the day. Seriously. If your numbers come out too high then that's fine, all the usual advice still applies. Change your diet, go for more walks, drink less beer. Not generally something we encourage but if it gives you more years to read books, then hey, bring it on.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;That's... about all there is to say, really. Unless you want to learn some more cool shit about blood pressure tests? Okay, strap in.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The word 'systole' comes from the Greek meaning 'contraction, drawing together'. 'Diastole', you won't be surprised to learn, is Greek for 'drawing apart, dilation'. The reason mercury is Hg on the periodic table, by the way? Because in Latin it's 'hydragyrum'... literally 'liquid silver'. The first guy to measure blood pressure inside an artery was called Stephen Hales, an English clergyman, and he did it in the 18th century by sticking tubes in horses. Then an Austrian guy called Samuel Siegfried Karl Ritter von Basch came along and invented the sphygmomanometer (told you). Speaking of animals, did you know giraffes have an insane blood pressure at the heart of 220/180? By the time it gets all the way up the neck to the brain it's pretty normal at 110/70. Giraffes are cool.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;And here's the thing - in the time it took us to google up all this shit and throw it in an article, we probably could have got our blood pressure checked. What did I tell you about modern men being easily distracted! &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Oh, and by the way. When you post a picture of you getting tested - which we do with every challenge so our goons can cheer each other on - make sure you get that hashtag correct #BPTest. If you don't get the capitals right we can't tick you off for a challenge coin.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Seriously. This is the type of shit that gives us high blood pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="featured-images text-center"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
 &lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/642924e7918ca780179170.jpg" style="max-width: 100%" /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 11:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/tgbc_monthly_challenge_bptest</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mayfield Chapter Opening</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mayfield, near Newcastle NSW, is home to one of the newest chapters of the Tough Guy Book Club (TGBC); a network of men’s book clubs held in pubs around the country and overseas, committed to getting men reading, catching up, and putting decent conversation back in the pub. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;New TGBC chapters start for a few different reasons. Someone moves away from their chapter and has the gumption to get one going, a bloke living in a book club desert discovers TGBC online or through distant friends and starts one from scratch, or as is the case here, a chapter becomes too big and splits. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Attendance at the Newcastle chapter had been high for months, 18 goons squeezing around a table in the backroom of The Blind Monk was getting unmanageable. Side chats, interruptions, general disorder – we were keeping it together, but it was bloody close to chaos. There was a tonne of interesting input, but it didn’t feel like everyone was getting a fair go. Hell, they were calling last drinks just as we were getting good and rowdy. Something had to give.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Splitting a TGBC chapter is bittersweet. There is excitement in the adventure; a new pub, potential new goons, and a breakaway spirit is tempered by the sorrow of losing the legends you won’t be catching up with each month. I have experienced a spilt before and still miss the contributions from regulars. What did Jez think about the magical realism in Sharks in the Time of Saviours? How was Jom’s trip to India? Did Monty finish the book on the day of the meet again?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;After an enjoyable search of options, The Stag and Hunter Hotel was chosen as the new venue. The spot we have carved out for ourselves is perfect –between the bistro and back bar it feels part of the action of the pub, while being removed enough to hear the conversation. Plus, it has stag heads!
 The first Mayfield meeting was to discuss The Outsiders by SE Hinton. The Newcastle chapter was relieved of five goons that night to discuss the 60s teenage gang culture of Oklahoma, in a new setting. It was fucking great! The small crowd was poles apart from the recent chats we have been part of. While I am looking forward to the chapter growing, it was enjoyable to experience a discussion this intimate, to learn a bit more about the others and share more than would have otherwise been possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="featured-images text-center"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
 &lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/64292456a7bd8618505880.jpg" style="max-width: 100%" /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 11:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/mayfield_chapter_opening</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TGBC Short Stories By Goons</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re a regular Goon, you know that each month we set a challenge for Goons to complete. Sometimes it’s a health challenge, like get your blood pressure checked. Sometimes it’s something simple like “do a thing” or “drink a beverage”. Back in October of 2022, we asked Goons to complete what was probably our toughest challenge yet - write a short story.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;But, as usual, there was a kicker. The story had to be submitted by 31 October 2022 and it had to make mention of a key and an offer.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Why did we need the writers to mention those things? Because the club had an idea… We wanted to see what would happen if we took the concept of the beloved Australian short film festival “Tropfest” and made it arm-wrestle a bunch of Goons. That’s right - we were starting our very own short story competition.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Now, Tough Guy Book Club is excited to announce that our first-ever collection of short stories is almost ready for publication! We received over 100 entries from Goons around the world, and each one imaginatively included mentions of a key and an offer. After carefully reviewing each submission, we have chosen our shortlist for publication, and we even have a special judge lined up to decide the best of the best!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;But wait, there’s more! Presales of the anthology, Short Stories By Goons - Volume One are now open on the website.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Don't miss out on your chance to grab a copy of what we hope is the first of an annual series. As well as showing your support for fellow Goons who made it through to the final selection, you may even find some inspiration for our next volume in this unique collection! &lt;a href="https://toughguybookclub.com/products"&gt;Order your copy today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="featured-images text-center"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
 &lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/63e5e46ec2f21859898831.jpg" style="max-width: 100%" /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 11:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/tgbc_short_stories_by_goons</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TGBC Monthly Challenge - #OpShop</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Op shops. Charity shops, secondhand stores, Vinnies, Salvos, the Goodwill. Call them whatever you like, wherever you are.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;For some they're a curiosity, a ubiquitous presence on your small town strip. For others they're a place you were supposed to go to drop off that box of old shit in the boot of the car, but you never got around to it. Some would argue they're a whole way of life - clothes, shoes, kitchenware, appliances, furniture, vinyl records (big surprise, we like those too). You can get anything at the op shop.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;If you've been to your local one recently, you might have seen a middle-aged man standing by the bookshelves, wrestling with his phone to get an extreme close-up selfie of his own left nostril.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;That's because the December 2022 challenge for Tough Guy Book Club was to go browse the cracked and faded spines at your local #opshop.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;TGBC has a wide range of attitudes to book ownership. We've talked about this a lot - some of us like them new and pristine in matched special editions. Some of us jam them in our back pockets and beach bags, dog-ear the pages and beat them all to hell. Others don't even care about physical copies anymore because the future is in the infinite e-reader and audiobook libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Point is there's a lot of paperbacks out there. Lots of them end up in the op shop. Some of them are going to be garbage, because of course. Shitty fantasy, romance novels with man-boob on the cover, thrillers by guys called Name SURNAME.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Bu you can't deny there's something special about cocking your head painfully sideways and shuffling along a row of wobbly fixtures. Your head racing with names and titles. Sorting the ones you know from the ones you've vaguely heard of, and the ones you have no idea about but might give a shot. Every now and then you slip one out with your index finger, check the back cover. Maybe even open and read the first sentence. The good ones get tucked under your arm. And sometimes, if you're lucky, you strike gold. A first edition of a book you've never read by your favourite author! You gasp out loud and everybody in the shop looks at you funny. But you don't care as you do a little happy dance up to the counter, say hello to the lady and pay about 75 cents for the whole lot.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Book shopping is fucking great, right?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Of course there are other benefits. It's good to reuse and recycle, it gets you out into the community, and puts money in the pockets of organisations which - like ours - are trying to do some good. For many this month it was a good excuse to catch up with other goons, grab a coffee, perhaps even bring the partner and kids along for this most sacred TGBC activity.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Maybe we'll start a secondhand revolution that will single-handedly fix our social ills and save the planet? Or maybe we'll just add to the big pile on the bedside table.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Either way it'll be fun. Shop on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="featured-images text-center"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
 &lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/640e72c2b8433626011511.jpg" style="max-width: 100%" /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 11:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/tgbc_monthly_challenge_opshop</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TGBC &amp; International Day for the Elimination of Violence Against Women</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 25 is host to the International Day for the Elimination of Violence Against Women and we marked the occasion with a very special meeting of Tough Guy Book Club.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tough Guy Book Club’s mission is to have men read more, talk more, and make more friends.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Where this mission takes place is in a scattering of pubs dotted around the world that play host to some big rowdy conversations about big important issues. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One of the biggest we’ve got to talk about is that of violence against women and the experience of women who face this scourge the world over, daily. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A difficult, necessary conversation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;For this special TGBC meeting on November 25, Goons were encouraged to invite an important woman in their life to come along.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The evening followed the same format as our tried-and-tested monthly meetings, but this time with the welcome addition of wives, girlfriends, aunties, sisters and mothers. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Taking over the entire upper floor of the Lord Newry Hotel in Fitzroy North, we made an Acknowledgement of Country and split into seven groups at seven tables. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Each group nominated a meeting “President” who welcomed guests, reported our monthly news and invited introductions from each guest in attendance before kicking off the discussion of that evening’s book - “Wild, Fearless Chests” by Melbourne author Mandy Beaumont.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Brutal”, “Gut wrenching”, “Heartbreaking” …&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;…were some of the most repeated words from our conversation about this debut novel of short stories.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Each story turns a dazzling spotlight into the darker corners and fringes of female experience, exposing rape, domestic violence and paedophilia in harrowing, high- definition.
 During the chat, this granular detail led many of us to agree that where “gritty” clearly couldn’t do the book justice, maybe “visceral” came at least a little closer to the true awfulness of the lives - and deaths - of the women portrayed. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;As our conversations went on over the evening, some of the women at our table shared insights from their own day-to-day lives that sadly (lamentably) mirrored those explored in “Wild, Fearless Chests”. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our discussion gave the men present not just “food for thought”, but rather a feast of bitter insights that - to sum up many Goons that night - left a lump in the throat and an appetite to better understand support, equality and allyship. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why we did this&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;That evening of November 25, Tough Guy Book Club did something a little different, by inviting the important women of our lives to talk with us about a traumatic exploration of women’s’ lives. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;That conversation was not an easy one to have. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;It was not a “fun” one to have. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;But it is part of a larger, ongoing conversation about gender-based violence that will still never, EVER be more difficult than what the victims of that same violence go through. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Why we did this may be summed up in the words of Margaret “Meg” Wheatley, that “Very great change starts from very small conversations, held among people who care”. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;hr&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tough Guy Book Club would like to thank the important women in our lives who joined our meeting this November 25.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We’d also like to thank that awesome crew over at Safe+Equal for supporting that meeting and show our appreciation for the excellent work they do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="featured-images text-center"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
 &lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/6427fc6ce6b49079287659.png" style="max-width: 100%" /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 11:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/tgbc_international_day_for_the_elimination_of_violence_against_women</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seattle Chapter Opening</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is supposed to be about the opening of one of our new international chapters, a chapter in Seattle, Washington, but we can’t do that without first talking about the chapter founder, Jeff. We’re an Australian based book club for men, but we have opened international chapters when a Goon moves overseas. Jeff isn’t a Goon who moved overseas though, so how did he find us?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;There’s two things you need to know about Jeff: he likes to read and he’s probably got one of the top 10 beards in the club. The beard was a bit of an accident. He’s been growing it since 2018 after he had knee surgery and couldn’t stand up for long enough to shave, then he just kept it. And starting a TGBC chapter in Seattle was a bit of an accident as well.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Looking for a book club to join, Jeff Googled “men’s book club near me” and was brought to the TGBC website for some reason. We’re no geography experts, but it looks like Jeff’s closest chapter was going to be in Townsville. Thanks Google…&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;So Jeff took a punt. He noticed we had a chapter in New York, Portland, and London. So why not start one in Seattle. A couple emails later and a few video calls with the TGBC crew in Melbourne, and he was on his way to starting the first TGBC chapter in Seattle.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Any new chapter for TGBC is a good thing, but we reckon new international chapters are the best thing. Book club is a great way to meet new people and always have a friend to have a drink with, wherever you may be travelling. There’s not many towns in Australia where you can’t find a TGBC member to meet and, as we expand overseas, there won’t be many cities worldwide either.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Ultimately, friendship is what this club is about. Some guys pretend it’s about the books, some pretend it’s about an excuse to go to the pub. And maybe that’s what attracts men to TGBC to start with. But it’s the friendships that keep people coming back and get people more involved in the club. The anonymous Goon writing this article knows all this too well; he started a chapter after moving to a new town.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;And yeah, that’s a message to all of you who are thinking about applying to start a new TGBC chapter. There’s a bit of commitment involved but it’s damn fulfilling.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Anyway, back to the new Seattle chapter of Tough Guy Book Club…&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Jeff chose Chuck’s Hop Shop in Greenwood because he liked the joint and it had good coverage between the north and the south of the city, perfect for attracting as many new goons as possible. From there, Jeff went old school and unusual with promotions: fliers at supermarkets, a poster at his venue, and even posters above the urinals in the bar bathroom.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;And it seemed to work! The Seattle chapter is boasting about 6 or 7 Goons and growing strong. Seattle is a big city, so hopefully one day soon we’ll see the club expanding to the other Chuck’s Hop Shop locations in the Central District and Steward Park. Hell, they can be the official TGBC venue of the greater SeaTac area. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;“We actually got so much interest in the first event that I was a little worried.” Jeff tells us. “Something like 50 people responded as ‘interested’ in our first meeting. Obviously they didn’t all show!”&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;And that’s a pretty typical thing we see with both old and new chapters. Potential new Goons have the best of intentions but never make it. If you’re one of those potential Goons who keeps responding to our Facebook events but never shows, we have something to say to you: keep responding, but do show up eventually. We’d love to have you. We get it. We all have the best of intentions then shit gets in the way. Keep responding, keep skipping, but feel guilty about it. Then come, have fun, and regret that it took you so bloody long.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;If you like reading, making new friends, or just want an excuse to have a beer, check out Chuck’s Hop Shop at 656 NW 85th Street in Seattle on the first Wednesday of every month at 7PM. If there are posters for TGBC above the urinals, you’re in the right place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="featured-images text-center"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
 &lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/6482accc24886108673294.jpg" style="max-width: 100%" /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 11:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/seattle_chapter_opening</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TGBC Monthly Challenge - #Short story</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been around the club for more than a few minutes, you’ll know we have a monthly challenge. The challenge is something different each month, but it always involves doing something to make yourself or your community better. When you do it, you post what you did on Facebook with a hashtag to prove you did it. Maybe it’s getting your blood pressure checked (one we do every year), maybe it’s planting a tree, maybe it’s having a beer with someone you haven’t had a beer with.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;TGBC challenges are meant to be moderately difficult but not impossible. For some Goons it pushes them to do something they don’t usually do or haven’t done in awhile, which is hard. Sometimes it’s just finding the time to do it - we all have lives outside of club, mostly.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The October challenge was set to be a bit different. One to separate the tough guys from the really tough guys. And to change things up, there was no hashtag to prove we did it!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;What was this challenge? &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Write a short story between 2,000 and 5,000 words. Not only that, but the story also needed to somehow feature a key and some sort of offer. Interpret that however you like. Write your story and prove you did it by emailing it to the club (see, no hashtag…).&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;As a group of men who like to read, this challenge looked simple to begin with. But just because a guy reads a lot doesn’t mean he can write. News around the club was, although we all liked having a crack at our own writing, it wasn’t that bloody easy.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A lot of Goons managed to bang out a decent 1,000 words, even 1,500 words, then started to struggle. It made us all wonder how an author could write an entire damned novel. How long is a novel supposed to be anyway?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;But, like the tough guys we are, we struggled through even though it was hard. Obviously some found it easier than others; we don’t talk about work here, but we’re sure there are a few professional writers in the club. For some Goons it was a bit of a sprint/stumble to finish, flinging words on a page just to get to that magical 2,000 words. Others had to cut things back.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Even some of the guys who write about the club regularly (i.e. the Goon writing this article right now) saw the challenge in this challenge. Banging out articles about TGBC is one thing, but trying to create a longer narrative is another. The process was basically “type, type, type,” check word count, “type, type, type.” But, from personal experience, this Goon found it rewarding, even if it just meant it reinforces what he likes to write about.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;But we got there and we got a pretty cool collection of short stories. And in true TGBC fashion, we designed a bitchin’ book to house the short stories. It has a picture of a skeleton at a typewriter on it, because we like skulls and skeletons and stuff like that. If you want it, you can buy it in &lt;a href="https://toughguybookclub.com/products"&gt;our store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;But really, shameless plug aside, we’re really proud of the Goons who had a go at writing. For many of them it was their first try at writing, but a few of those guys found they liked writing and continue to do so. For others, it wasn’t for them. But they challenged themselves and created something, and that was kind of the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="featured-images text-center"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
 &lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/63e5e428ceedf507217583.jpg" style="max-width: 100%" /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 11:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/tgbc_monthly_challenge_short_story</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TGBC SHORT STORY COMPETITION</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This months TGBC Challenge is to write a short story.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;By 31 October 2022, you need to write the draft of a short story (between 2,000 and 5,000 words) and send it to us. It just needs to be a first draft mind you, you’ll have more time to fix it up later, so go for speed over precision. The best of these stories as chosen by our judges and will be published in the first annual Tough Guy Book Club short story collection.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This collection will be officially launched in March at the Clunes Booktown Festival 2023. Your story must include these two elements - a key and an offer. Other than that, your story can be as wild as you like. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Keep reading for the full terms and conditions and details on how to submit your story.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TOUGH GUY BOOK CLUB SHORT STORY COMPETITION CONDITIONS OF ENTRY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ol&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Entrants must have attended one Tough Guy Book Club chapter meeting between July 2022 and October 2022. If an entrant has not been able to attend a chapter meet during the time frame, entrants may be accepted from Goons with an enduring connection to club, &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Entries may be accepted from those Goons unable to attend a recent chapter meeting, but have an enduring connection to Tough Guy Book Club, subject to the discretion of the judges.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Entrants must be 18 years or more at the closing date of the competition.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;All works must be in English, typed in 12-point sized font, 1.5 spaced using Arial or Calibri.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Entries must be original work and the entrant’s own work.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;There is a limit of two entries per person (including anyone writing under a pseudonym).&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Entries submitted to this competition cannot also be entered into any other competitions or awards at the same time.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Entries must not have won a previous award or competition.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Entries must be unpublished at the time of submission and remain unpublished (in print or any online publication, including self-publication) until after the shortlist and winner is announced in March 2023. &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Entries are submitted unencumbered and without restrictions, with full first publication rights available to Tough Guy Book Club and/or a nominated publisher. Copyright for all work will remain with the author.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;The author’s name, biography and image may be used in marketing and publicity materials associated with the Tough Guy Book Club.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;In order to preserve anonymity and the ‘blind’ judging process, uploaded manuscripts must only contain the title of the story. Any personal identification (e.g. author’s name) relating to the entrant must not appear anywhere on the manuscript, including in the header or footer.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;All decisions about entries and creating a shortlist for the competition are final and we will not enter into correspondence about them. All decisions about judging for the competition winner are final and we will not enter into correspondence about them either.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;The judges will not be required to make an award if they do not consider the entries to be of sufficient standard.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Any entries that are considered by the Tough Guy Book Club Short Story Competition - in its absolute discretion - to be of an offensive nature, will be rejected.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Only those writers shortlisted for publication will be notified.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Writing must be works of fiction.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Length must be between 2,000 and 5,000 words.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Stories must include the following elements within the body of the work: a key and an offer.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Closing date for entries:
 &lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;First drafts must be submitted via email to &lt;strong&gt;daniel@toughguybookclub.com,&lt;/strong&gt; or as otherwise directed, by 11:59pm Monday, October 31 2022&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Final manuscripts for must be submitted via email to &lt;strong&gt;daniel@toughguybookclub.com&lt;/strong&gt;, or as otherwise directed, by 11:59pm Saturday AEDT , January 7 2023.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;The winner of the 2022 Tough Guy Book Club Short Story Competition will be announced in March 2023 and published on &lt;a href="http://www.toughguybookclub.com"&gt;www.toughguybookclub.com&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ol&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SUBMITTING YOUR FINAL MANUSCRIPT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Your final manuscript must meet the following criteria in order to be considered for publication:&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ol&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Manuscripts must be delivered as a PDF document. No other formats will be accepted.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;All works must be in English, typed in 12-point sized font, 1.5 spaced using Arial or Calibri.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;The completed manuscript must be between 2,000 and 5,000 words.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Your manuscript must not feature the name of the author or any information that could reasonably identify the author on any page, including the header and footer.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Your completed manuscript must be a version of the same story submitted for your first draft (as received by the judges on 31 October 2022).&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;The subject line of your email submission must include the following: “TGBC Short Story - Completed Manuscript, Author’s Name”&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;The body of your email submission must include:
 &lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;The Author’s name (and chosen pen name, if applicable)&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;The name of your story&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;The name of the Tough Guy Book Club chapter you attended and the date of your most recent attendance&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;The author’s mobile phone number or best contact phone number&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Submissions that meet the above criteria must be delivered to &lt;strong&gt;daniel@toughguybookclub.com&lt;/strong&gt; or as otherwise directed, by 11:59pm Saturday AEDT , January 7 2023.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="featured-images text-center"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
 &lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/63773e6e0025e983674821.jpg" style="max-width: 100%" /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 11:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/tgbc_short_story_competition</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Day for the Elimination of Violence Against Women</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tough Guy Book Club is about men meeting in pubs to have rowdy conversations about big important issues. &lt;br&gt;
 And one of the biggest issues facing the world is violence against women.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;So on November 25, to mark the International Day for the Elimination of Violence Against Women, Tough Guy Book Club in partnership with Safe and Equal will host an extra-special open book club. Join us as we discuss the uncompromising 'Wild, Fearless Chests' by Melbourne author Mandy Beaumont, who will also be in attendance to help us with the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This is an open event, meaning goons are welcome - encouraged even - to bring an important women in their life. It's a free event, but tickets need to be booked to confirm numbers. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&lt;/strong&gt;: International Day for the Elimination of Violence Against Women book club event hosted by Tough Guy Book Club.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where&lt;/strong&gt;: Lord Newry Hotel, 543 Brunswick St, Fitzroy North
 When: November 25, 2022 from 7pm. Snacks willbe provided.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Book&lt;/strong&gt;: Wild, Fearless Chests by Mandy Beaumont. A free copy will be provided with your tickets.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.eventbrite.co.nz/e/tough-guy-book-club-elimination-of-violence-against-women-event-tickets-430328041757"&gt;Register Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="featured-images text-center"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
 &lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/633d3da206568107837950.jpeg" style="max-width: 100%" /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 11:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/international_day_for_the_elimination_of_violence_against_women</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goon Profile - Chas Lang</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 Chas Lang&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 Mornington Chapter&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who are you:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 So who am I? I'm I pretty ordinary 30-something guy. It's hard for 30-something guys to make new friends, but I found a way to do that. This isn't supposed to sound sad, but I'm a totally normal guy. I have a lot of hobbies outside of books, and all those hobbies are what I live for. I love my family, I like my job enough, but I like relaxing and hobbies more. I don't think there's anything wrong that there's nothing "special" about me. But I do like community, I'm really big on community, whatever that means.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How long have you been with TGBC:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 Not sure - Dan McMahon recruited me over the summer break when we were reading a brief history of seven killings - so a month of two after that meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you end up coming to TGBC:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 I love this story. When I was living in Sydney with my girlfriend (now wife) and we would drive back to Melbourne to visit family. We would stop in Beechworth on the way there and back, staying in the holiday park. We'd also always stopped at the brewery for a pizza and a beer whenever we were there. The brewery is always busy and the tables pretty close together. We ended up being at a two person table that was only a foot away from Dan MCMahon and his partner. We got talking and obviously Dan mentions bookclub. They met at the Shakespeare in Surry Hills, not far from my house. Honestly, at the time, it sounded like a fun enough night out, but something I wouldn't get into too much - I wanted to read more. Now I'm running a chapter and have friends across Australia because of this club. Says a lot about drinking too much and talking to strangers in a pub...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s your favourite TGBC book?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;
 This is an unfair question. I probably like/love about 60% of the books, medium on 30% of them, and dislike 10% of them. But I like that I pick up things I wouldn't pick up otherwise. If I really had to decide I'm going to go with Cannery Row by Steinbeck because I've read it about 10 times and is one of my favourite books I've ever read.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why are you a member of TGBC?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;
 For so many reasons: to make friends, to help my community, to read more, to read more of what I wouldn't read otherwise, to find guys with other hobbies that aren't reading, to learn from men older than me, to help men younger than me, to have something to do on the first Wednesday of the month.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you think a "Tough Guy" is?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;
 A DGSC who isn't scared about learning. Someone who isn't scared to speak his opinion but isn't scared to admit that he's wrong. Being able to admit you're wrong is important - I'm not saying spout an uneducated opinion, but there's so much to masculinity that is about being stubborn that's just stupid. A real tough guy can learn.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's your favourite library?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;
 I'll stick with the local - Mornington Library. Great and friendly staff, easy inter-library lone system.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What book have we not read yet that you’d like to do at TGBC:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;
 Fight Club - it's probably way cliched, but there's such a great exploration of masculinity in there it may be interesting. Then again, scratch that, it may be too easily misunderstood. Let's go with Fear and Loathing in Last Vegas - it's another good exploration of freedom and changing times that may not attract as many fuck heads who don't understand it.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What something people wouldn't know about you if they judged you by your cover?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;
 I'm an extremely anxious person. A lot of people think I'm very laid back but it's very much to the contrary. I don't mind sharing that. I think we need to normalise anxiety.
 Also for the attached photo - it's a photo of me at my favourite Scottish loch - Loch Lochy. It's the best loch because of its name. I FINALLY GOT THERE!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="featured-images text-center"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
 &lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/6411460564010487937117.jpg" style="max-width: 100%" /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/goon_profile_chas_lang</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sale Chapter Opens</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Tough Guy Book Club slowly takes over the towns, cities, and suburbs of Australia, one area has been an unexpected focus of our expansion plans: Gippsland. For a relatively rural area, Gippsland in South-East Victoria boasts four chapters.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;TGBC also has a bit of a new home in Gippsland. Our officially unofficial yearly camp location, Licola Wilderness Village is in Northern Gippsland. We’ve done camp there twice and vowed to return every year. In the past we’ve changed camp locations yearly, but we’ve fallen in love with Licola and it will forever be our home.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Sale was an interesting but not entirely unusual expansion of the club. Our Heyfield chapter (also in Gippsland) was losing a Goon, Clean Pete.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Clean Pete is no stranger to TGBC or starting new chapters. Longer ago than anybody cares to remember, Clean Pete joined the Castlemaine chapter, but decided to move back to his hometown of Heyfield to be closer to his mum. Although it’s a pretty small town, Heyfield remains one of our most successful chapters.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Sale proved to be a bit more of a challenge. Unlike Heyfield, where he had an existing network of friends to promote the club, Pete was relatively new to Sale, meaning it was harder to spread the good word. But that’s what local bookstores, op shops, and just talking to guys in pubs is for. Never underestimate the good conversations you can have with strangers in the pub.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Ultimately that's the story for many of us. We move to a new area and want to make friends with people who have similar interests. So we start a new book club chapter. And it works well. Not only to make friends but to learn about a new community and just get to know your way around.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;“I moved back to Heyfield for my mum,” Pete explained. “But after separating from my wife recently, I needed a bit of a sea change and a new start... Sale seemed good enough.”&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Sale does seem “good enough”, for TGBC at least. Far enough from Heyfield to get some new guys interested in books (or get guys already interested in books involved), near enough to expand our footprint. And Sale has a great venue for TGBC. The Gippsland Hotel (known as the Gippy) has a dedicated “reading room” that the Goons can take over on the first Wednesday of every month.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;And the reading room is getting plenty of use these days. The first Sale meeting talked plenty about the book (The Great Gatsby), but it was also a reunion of sorts. There were visitors from Heyfield. There was talk of motorbikes and local wildlife. There were warnings of the danger of the running over the latter while riding the former at night.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;If you want to meet Clean Pete and the Goons of Sale, join them at the Gippsland Hotel at 153 York Street on the first Wednesday of every month. Just ask the bar staff where the reading room is. They'll point you in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="featured-images text-center"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
 &lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/642925852cd58317848912.jpg" style="max-width: 100%" /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/sale_chapter_opens</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TGBC Monthly Challenge - #NewBloods</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been around Tough Guy Book Club for a while, you’ll know we do monthly challenges. These challenges range from something a little strange like our &lt;a href="https://toughguybookclub.com/news/monthly-challenge-unusualreading"&gt;unusual reading challenge&lt;/a&gt;, health related challenges like get your &lt;a href="https://toughguybookclub.com/news/monthly-challenge-bpcheck-2022"&gt;blood pressure checked&lt;/a&gt;, and club growth challenges like &lt;a href="https://toughguybookclub.com/news/tgbc-monthly-challange-newgoon"&gt;bringing a new goon to chapter&lt;/a&gt;. The August 2022 challenge is probably one of our most important yet: donate blood.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This challenge came about because, until recently, people who lived in the UK between 1980 and 1996 were unable to donate blood due to Mad Cow disease concerns. This restriction actually affected a huge amount of Goons so we didn’t want to make it a challenge until now. We’re not sure of the science behind why the restriction was lifted, but hell, donating blood is a good thing so let’s go get this done.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;So to take part in the challenge, Goons join the brand new TGBC lifeblood team, book in to donate, then snap a picture when they’re actually donating. This picture goes into Pool Hall with the hashtag #newbloods.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We’re not going to apologise for putting some stats and facts in this article because donating blood is, well, bloody important. Hopefully we can convince some more people to donate with some simple information. According to the good folk who take our blood, red blood cells last 42 days after they’re donated and Australia needs 1.7 million donations a year to those in need. It’s not like we can keep a reserve of blood. We need people constantly donating to save lives.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Donating blood is also pretty easy. All you need to do is drink a lot of water the day before (and the day of) then sit in a chair for a little while until about half a litre of your blood is drained out. Afterward they give you some juice to drink and even a sausage roll if you want. It’s not five star dining but gets your energy back up after losing about 8% of your blood volume. Then you leave knowing you’ve done your good deed for the day; you’ve probably just saved three lives.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;So far this month we’ve seen plenty of Goons donating for the first time, which is awesome. We’ve also seen plenty of Goons who regularly donate blood talking a whole lot more about it, which is also awesome. There’s also a few Goons who are sharing the various reasons they can’t donate blood. These Goons want to help but can’t do so directly, so they’re helping in their own way. Maybe they’re driving another Goon to the blood bank, maybe they’re organising things, or maybe they’re just sharing their story so we all better understand why it’s so important that those who can donate do donate. All in all, this challenge is really bringing the club together.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;If you want to donate blood, check out &lt;a href="https://www.lifeblood.com.au/blood"&gt;Lifeblood&lt;/a&gt; to book online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="featured-images text-center"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
 &lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/63292782ba909657255543.jpg" style="max-width: 100%" /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/tgbc_monthly_challenge_newbloods</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TGBC Monthly Challenge - #NewBloods</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;August 2022 saw one of our coolest challenges yet, with goons being encouraged to give blood as part of the TGBC Lifeblood donor team. Restrictions preventing former residents of the United Kingdom from donating had recently been lifted, so #NewBloods was perfectly timed to get more brothers involved in this lifesaving program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are plenty of valid reasons some of us cannot donate blood; however, goons of this ilk were still able to be involved. This may have meant providing transport or moral support for a donor, volunteering (those snacks don’t just prepare themselves!) or sharing their story to illustrate why donating is so important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This goon was a semi-regular donor when #NewBloods rolled up and its arrival added extra motivation to schedule that appointment and keep it. Suddenly I wasn’t just one man sitting in the chair; I was part of a team and could easily imagine goons across Australia - indeed, the world - with me in spirit and in purpose. And let me tell you folks, that was a very cool moment. Moreover, when I told Lifeblood staff about the challenge it was lauded all round and became the impetus for a conversation about TGBC and what we are all about. Suffice to say we are aces in their books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that is as it should be. Here’s what Red Cross had to say at the end of the month: “Just wanted to send you a massive thank you for all your support last month! Your Lifeblood team made 105 donations across Australia in August 2022 – of these 38 were new donors. Twenty-eight donations at Melbourne Donor Centre – of these 15 were new donors. Your lifeblood team ranked number 2 for highest new donors at Melbourne Donor Centre last month! And, Tough Guy Book Club is ranked number 3 highest new donors for August across the whole of Australia!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put all that in its proper perspective, 105 donations equates to 315 lives saved! If ever the satisfaction was in the giving, surely this was it. And we’re not done giving yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, our goal is to save 2000 lives. With the TGBC Lifeblood donor team numbering 172 goons, we’ve been able to chalk up 157 donations and save 471 lives in the first quarter alone. That's some impressive early momentum, to be certain. Let’s keep it going and make that ambitious goal our reality, blood brothers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking on at my shoulder as I give this piece a final proofread is the plasmapheresis machine. I can't help but smile as it beeps its approval. One hundred and fifty-eight donations…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="featured-images text-center"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="max-width: 100%;" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/648309f641b54371124518.png" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <author>Sara Fishburn</author>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/_tgbc_monthly_challenge_newbloods</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TGBC Monthly Challenge - #GuerrillaGardening</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;guer.ril.la (noun)
 A member of a small independent group taking part in irregular fighting, typically against larger regular forces. From the Spanish, diminutive of guerra meaning 'war'&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;+++&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;What's the first thing we learned from this month's challenge, where goons were tasked with planting a tree, shrub or bush somewhere they weren't allowed to, be it park, garden, or just on the bare-arse side of the road?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;First thing we learned is that 'guerrilla' is a very hard word to spell.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Also, hashtags are confusing. Not only do you need to get all those stupid vowels in the right order, you have to sprinkle in a weird number of Rs and Ls, then you have to decide between the noun and the verb, the thing-in-itself or the pastime-slash-concept more generally. So if you check our FB page you'll find #guerrillagarden and #guerrillagardening and #guerilla and #guerrila and who knows how many variations in between.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We kind of created an administrative nightmare for ourselves, to be honest. But hey, fuck it! Someone will trawl through all those to make sure you get your challenges ticked off, and we'll cope. We're just trying to do a little bit of good here, not fight a war.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Second thing we learned is that some of goons are already equipped with extremely green thumbs. We have seasoned gardeners who've been doing this for years - tending apricots and mulberries around the neighbourhood, shoring up unstable slopes with New Zealand flax, joining council initiatives to plant dozens of saplings in empty lots. These are people who own shovels and know the scientific names for shit. Not to be messed with. Thankfully they're also extremely nice and more than willing to share their expertise with the rest of us.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;That's the other group we learned about this month - the goons who aren't regular gardeners, don't get the time or the inclination, or just don't have a clue. Still, they got out there and gave it a go. Whether they were planting a flame tree (and getting the song stuck in all our heads for a week, thanks), sticking some native flowers in the nature strip, or just scattering a few veggie seeds by the roadside, every little bit helps.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Mostly I think we learned that Tough Guy Book Club really loves an adventure. Who doesn't want to take their kids to the community garden? Or go out after dark to help their friends dig a hole? Or sneak onto a golf course in the dead of night with [NAMES REDACTED]? After all, this was our challenge for July, also known as Hemingway month. In honour of a man who spent his entire life having adventures. Even if the consequences sometimes involved ending a marriage or crashing a plane.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This is why our challenges come with rules. If it's fun and good for you and the planet and doesn't hurt anybody, we say let's go.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Come on down next month and see what our next adventure will be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="featured-images text-center"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
 &lt;img alt="" src="https://tgbc-images.s3.ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/632980c325886082200384.jpg" style="max-width: 100%" /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.toughguybookclub.com/tgbc_monthly_challenge_guerrillagardening</link>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
